<OperationalPackets VERSION="0.3.0">
  <ExecutionPacketTemplate>
    <!-- Canonical controller-to-worker execution packet. -->
    <ExecutionPacket>
      <module-id>M-EXAMPLE</module-id>
      <module-name>ExampleDomain</module-name>
      <purpose>Implement the approved module without architectural drift.</purpose>
      <write-scope>
        <file-1>src/example/index.ts</file-1>
        <file-2>src/example/index.test.ts</file-2>
      </write-scope>
      <contract-excerpt><![CDATA[
Planned module contract excerpt goes here.
      ]]></contract-excerpt>
      <graph-entry-excerpt><![CDATA[
Knowledge graph entry excerpt goes here.
      ]]></graph-entry-excerpt>
      <dependency-contract-summaries>
        <dependency-1 module="M-LOGGER">Structured logger interface with stable marker fields.</dependency-1>
      </dependency-contract-summaries>
      <verification-excerpt><![CDATA[
Verification-plan excerpt goes here.
      ]]></verification-excerpt>
      <expected-graph-delta-fields>
        <field-1>imports</field-1>
        <field-2>exports</field-2>
        <field-3>annotations</field-3>
        <field-4>CrossLinks</field-4>
      </expected-graph-delta-fields>
      <expected-verification-delta-fields>
        <field-1>test-files</field-1>
        <field-2>module-checks</field-2>
        <field-3>required-log-markers</field-3>
        <field-4>follow-up-checks</field-4>
      </expected-verification-delta-fields>
      <notes>
        <note-1>Workers should only read more context when the packet is insufficient.</note-1>
      </notes>
    </ExecutionPacket>
  </ExecutionPacketTemplate>

  <GraphDeltaTemplate>
    <!-- Canonical worker-to-controller graph delta. -->
    <GraphDelta module="M-EXAMPLE">
      <imports-added>
        <import-1>M-LOGGER</import-1>
      </imports-added>
      <imports-removed />
      <exports-added>
        <export-1>runExample</export-1>
      </exports-added>
      <exports-removed />
      <annotations-added>
        <annotation-1>&lt;fn-runExample PURPOSE="Execute the example flow" /&gt;</annotation-1>
      </annotations-added>
      <annotations-removed />
      <cross-links-added>
        <CrossLink from="M-EXAMPLE" to="M-LOGGER" relation="uses" />
      </cross-links-added>
      <cross-links-removed />
      <notes>
        <note-1>Only list graph facts that really changed in the code.</note-1>
      </notes>
    </GraphDelta>
  </GraphDeltaTemplate>

  <VerificationDeltaTemplate>
    <!-- Canonical worker-to-controller verification delta. -->
    <VerificationDelta module="M-EXAMPLE">
      <test-files-added>
        <file-1>src/example/index.test.ts</file-1>
      </test-files-added>
      <test-files-removed />
      <module-checks>
        <command-1>bun test src/example/index.test.ts</command-1>
        <command-2>bun x tsc --noEmit</command-2>
      </module-checks>
      <required-log-markers>
        <marker-1>[ExampleDomain][runExample][BLOCK_EXECUTE_FLOW]</marker-1>
      </required-log-markers>
      <required-trace-assertions>
        <assertion-1>Failure path must not emit BLOCK_PERSIST_RESULT.</assertion-1>
      </required-trace-assertions>
      <wave-follow-up>
        <item-1>Run merged-surface integration check for the logger adapter.</item-1>
      </wave-follow-up>
      <phase-follow-up>
        <item-1>Run the broader regression suite before marking the phase done.</item-1>
      </phase-follow-up>
    </VerificationDelta>
  </VerificationDeltaTemplate>

  <FailurePacketTemplate>
    <!-- Canonical verification-to-fixer failure handoff. -->
    <FailurePacket>
      <scenario>Primary success path fails on valid input.</scenario>
      <contract-ref>M-EXAMPLE / V-M-EXAMPLE / scenario-1</contract-ref>
      <expected-evidence>
        <marker-1>[ExampleDomain][runExample][BLOCK_VALIDATE_INPUT]</marker-1>
        <assertion-1>Expected return value should equal "ok".</assertion-1>
      </expected-evidence>
      <observed-evidence>
        <log-1>[ExampleDomain][runExample][BLOCK_VALIDATE_INPUT] emitted</log-1>
        <trace-1>BLOCK_VALIDATE_INPUT -> threw EXAMPLE_INVALID_STATE</trace-1>
      </observed-evidence>
      <first-divergent-block>BLOCK_VALIDATE_INPUT</first-divergent-block>
      <suggested-next-action>Read the contract, inspect the divergent block, and apply the smallest safe fix.</suggested-next-action>
    </FailurePacket>
  </FailurePacketTemplate>

  <ProjectExecutionPackets>
    <ExecutionPacket packet-id="M-CONTRACTS-wave-1" module="M-CONTRACTS" phase="Phase-1" step="1" verification-ref="V-M-CONTRACTS">
      <module-id>M-CONTRACTS</module-id>
      <module-name>Contracts</module-name>
      <purpose>Freeze the canonical contract package against the lossless GRACE SSOT so every later control-plane and adapter step consumes the same OpenAPI, schema, WebSocket, webhook, enum, and worker DTO surface.</purpose>
      <write-scope>
        <file-1>packages/contracts/openapi/openapi.yaml</file-1>
        <file-2>packages/contracts/schemas/common/enums.schema.json</file-2>
        <file-3>packages/contracts/schemas/common/error-envelope.schema.json</file-3>
        <file-4>packages/contracts/schemas/common/job-snapshot.schema.json</file-4>
        <file-5>packages/contracts/schemas/http/create-transcription-upload.schema.json</file-5>
        <file-6>packages/contracts/schemas/http/create-transcription-from-url.schema.json</file-6>
        <file-7>packages/contracts/schemas/http/create-report.schema.json</file-7>
        <file-8>packages/contracts/schemas/http/create-deep-research.schema.json</file-8>
        <file-9>packages/contracts/schemas/http/job-control.schema.json</file-9>
        <file-10>packages/contracts/schemas/http/artifact-resolution.schema.json</file-10>
        <file-11>packages/contracts/schemas/internal/worker-control.schema.json</file-11>
        <file-12>packages/contracts/ws/job-event.schema.json</file-12>
        <file-13>packages/contracts/webhook/job-lifecycle.schema.json</file-13>
        <file-14>packages/contracts/tests/test_contract_surfaces.py</file-14>
      </write-scope>
      <write-scope-notes>
        <note-1>Repository state is still pre-monorepo, so this step creates the minimal `packages/contracts` tree needed for the frozen public surface.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not broaden into `packages/sdk-ts`, `packages/sdk-py`, `apps/api`, `workers/*`, `apps/web`, or compose/bootstrap files in this step.</note-2>
      </write-scope-notes>
      <contract-excerpt><![CDATA[
DevelopmentPlan / M-CONTRACTS:
- Purpose: provide the canonical API, WebSocket, webhook, enum, and validation contracts for the entire platform.
- Scope: OpenAPI routes, shared schemas, public enums, webhook envelopes, WebSocket envelopes, and internal worker DTOs.
- Links: M-CONTRACTS, V-M-CONTRACTS, DF-001, DF-003, DF-007.
- Note: this module must be complete before the first large implementation wave.

PublicApiContract + WebSocketContract + InternalWorkerContract:
- Create endpoints support optional Idempotency-Key, but retry is intentionally non-idempotent.
- If delivery strategy is webhook, a webhook URL is required.
- The existing upload endpoint preserves one-file-to-one-job semantics, while combined multi-media transcription uses a separate `/v1/transcription-jobs/combined` endpoint.
- WebSocket envelope and webhook envelope carry versioned event fields, but polling remains the authoritative read path.
- Internal worker claim, progress, artifact, finalize, and cancel-check DTOs are part of the same frozen contract surface, and claim returns ordered inputs rather than assuming a single source.

ImplementationOrder / Phase-1 + DefinitionOfDone + ExecutionRules:
- Phase-1 step-1 converts the migration plan into canonical OpenAPI, JSON schema, WebSocket, and webhook contracts.
- Freeze polling, webhook, retry, cancel, idempotency, child reuse, and multi-file upload semantics before any major code wave.
- Do not treat webhook delivery or WebSocket as stronger than polling.
      ]]></contract-excerpt>
      <graph-entry-excerpt><![CDATA[
KnowledgeGraph / M-CONTRACTS:
- Path: packages/contracts
- Depends: none
- Verification ref: V-M-CONTRACTS
- Purpose: own shared OpenAPI, JSON schema, webhook, WebSocket, and enum contracts that every runtime surface depends on.
- Public annotations already expected in the graph:
  - export-openapi
  - export-websocket-schema
  - export-webhook-schema
  - type-JobSnapshot
  - type-DeliveryStrategy
  - type-ArtifactResolution
  - type-WorkerFinalizeRequest
  - type-SourceSet

Existing CrossLinks:
- M-CONTRACTS -> M-API-HTTP relation="defines-public-contracts-for"
- M-API-HTTP -> M-CONTRACTS relation="depends-on-contracts-from"
      ]]></graph-entry-excerpt>
      <dependency-contract-summaries>
        <dependency-1 module="none">No upstream module dependencies. This freeze point is consumed next by M-API-STORAGE, M-API-QUEUE, M-API-JOBS, M-API-EVENTS, M-API-HTTP, and M-WORKER-COMMON.</dependency-1>
      </dependency-contract-summaries>
      <verification-excerpt><![CDATA[
VerificationPlan / TestingStrategy / V-M-CONTRACTS / Gate-Phase-1:
- Contract tests must cover OpenAPI validation, JSON schema tests for WebSocket and webhook envelopes, SDK compatibility expectations, and delivery-strategy plus idempotency normalization.
- Module check: validate OpenAPI, JSON schemas, and enum surfaces against the frozen design decisions.
- Success scenario: polling and webhook create requests share the same canonical job snapshot envelope.
- Success scenario: combined transcription create request preserves one-job semantics while reusing the canonical job snapshot envelope.
- Failure scenario: invalid delivery strategy or missing webhook URL is rejected deterministically.
- Required marker: [Contracts][validateContractSurface][BLOCK_VALIDATE_CONTRACT_SURFACE]
- Required assertion: retry remains non-idempotent while create endpoints support Idempotency-Key.
- Module readiness target: ready-after-contract-tests.
- Phase gate evidence: polling, webhook, retry, cancel, idempotency, and child reuse semantics must be represented in contracts and verification before Phase-2 begins.
      ]]></verification-excerpt>
      <step-local-verification>
        <command-1>.venv/bin/python -m pytest packages/contracts/tests/test_contract_surfaces.py</command-1>
        <command-2>Contract-specific schema validation covering OpenAPI, shared enums, webhook, WebSocket, and internal worker DTO coherence.</command-2>
        <evidence-1>The same canonical job snapshot and error envelope are reused across per-file upload, combined upload, URL, child-create, cancel, retry, artifact-resolve, WebSocket, and webhook surfaces.</evidence-1>
        <evidence-2>Wave follow-up remains SDK regeneration only; broader phase follow-up is freezing the contract diff before M-API-STORAGE and M-API-QUEUE start.</evidence-2>
      </step-local-verification>
      <expected-graph-delta-fields>
        <field-1>imports: remain none unless the final file layout introduces a shared helper strictly inside `packages/contracts`.</field-1>
        <field-2>exports: confirm `export-openapi`, `export-validationSchemas`, `export-websocket-schema`, `export-webhook-schema`, and the shared public types already annotated in the knowledge graph.</field-2>
        <field-3>annotations: refine only package-level contract annotations that become public and stable after this freeze.</field-3>
        <field-4>CrossLinks: no new module links are expected in this step; adjust only if the real public contract surface materially differs from the current graph entry.</field-4>
      </expected-graph-delta-fields>
      <expected-verification-delta-fields>
        <field-1>test-files: add concrete `packages/contracts/tests/*` coverage for OpenAPI, shared schemas, WS, webhook, and worker DTO coherence.</field-1>
        <field-2>module-checks: preserve a narrow contract-validation command set and record the exact command that becomes authoritative.</field-2>
        <field-3>required-log-markers: preserve `[Contracts][validateContractSurface][BLOCK_VALIDATE_CONTRACT_SURFACE]` for the schema validation path.</field-3>
        <field-4>follow-up-checks: keep wave follow-up focused on SDK regeneration and phase follow-up focused on contract freeze before control-plane implementation.</field-4>
      </expected-verification-delta-fields>
      <notes>
        <note-1>Start by freezing shared enums, the delivery model, job snapshot envelope, error envelope, and artifact-resolution shape; route-specific schemas should reuse those shapes instead of re-declaring them.</note-1>
        <note-2>Model multipart and JSON create flows as semantically aligned after defaulting `delivery.strategy=polling`, but preserve the split between per-file upload and explicit combined upload semantics.</note-2>
        <note-3>Include internal worker claim, progress, cancel-check, artifacts, and finalize DTOs in the first freeze because M-WORKER-COMMON depends on those contracts immediately after Phase-2 foundation work starts.</note-3>
        <note-4>Keep polling authoritative in every schema and example. WebSocket and webhook are delivery layers, not stronger read models.</note-4>
      </notes>
    </ExecutionPacket>

    <ExecutionPacket packet-id="M-INFRA-COMPOSE-wave-1" module="M-INFRA-COMPOSE" phase="Phase-1" step="2" verification-ref="V-M-INFRA-COMPOSE">
      <module-id>M-INFRA-COMPOSE</module-id>
      <module-name>InfraCompose</module-name>
      <purpose>Freeze the local runtime topology and validation scaffolding so later API, worker, UI, Telegram, and MCP steps land inside one canonical compose boundary instead of improvising service wiring per module.</purpose>
      <write-scope>
        <file-1>infra/docker-compose.yml</file-1>
        <file-2>infra/env/*.env.example</file-2>
        <file-3>infra/scripts/compose-smoke.sh</file-3>
      </write-scope>
      <write-scope-notes>
        <note-1>This Phase-1 step defines topology and config-validation scaffolding; it does not implement the API, workers, UI, or adapters themselves.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not broaden into `apps/api`, `workers/*`, `apps/web`, `apps/telegram-bot`, `apps/mcp-server`, or runtime code while executing this packet.</note-2>
      </write-scope-notes>
      <contract-excerpt><![CDATA[
DevelopmentPlan / M-INFRA-COMPOSE:
- Purpose: own local Docker Compose topology, service dependencies, and environment contracts.
- Scope: compose topology, healthchecks, startup ordering, volumes, service env contracts, and smoke-run expectations.
- Links: M-INFRA-COMPOSE, V-M-INFRA-COMPOSE, DF-001, DF-003, DF-006, DF-007.
- Note: this step prepares the canonical runtime boundary before service implementation spreads across later phases.

ComposeDesign + RepositoryShape + EnvironmentContracts:
- Define required services for postgres, redis, minio, api, worker-transcription, worker-report, worker-deep-research, web, telegram-bot, and mcp-server.
- Freeze healthcheck expectations, named volumes, env-file layout, and startup ordering assumptions in one compose-owned surface.
- Because the service modules are not implemented yet, Phase-1 verification is config-level and smoke-scaffold-level rather than full stack boot.

ImplementationOrder / Phase-1 step-2:
- Define required runtime topology, services, and health expectations in a GRACE-governed shape before Phase-2 begins.
      ]]></contract-excerpt>
      <graph-entry-excerpt><![CDATA[
KnowledgeGraph / M-INFRA-COMPOSE:
- Path: infra/docker-compose.yml
- Depends: M-API-HTTP, M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION, M-WORKER-REPORT, M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH, M-WEB-UI, M-TELEGRAM-ADAPTER, M-MCP-ADAPTER
- Verification ref: V-M-INFRA-COMPOSE
- Purpose: define and bootstrap the local runtime topology for API, workers, adapters, and storage dependencies.
- Public annotations already expected in the graph:
  - export-composeStack

Existing CrossLinks:
- M-INFRA-COMPOSE -> M-API-HTTP relation="runs"
- M-INFRA-COMPOSE -> M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION relation="runs"
- M-INFRA-COMPOSE -> M-WORKER-REPORT relation="runs"
- M-INFRA-COMPOSE -> M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH relation="runs"
      ]]></graph-entry-excerpt>
      <dependency-contract-summaries>
        <dependency-1 module="future-service-modules">Compose depends on later service modules conceptually, but this Phase-1 packet only freezes their runtime slots, not their implementations.</dependency-1>
        <dependency-2 module="M-CONTRACTS">The topology must respect the already-frozen control-plane versus adapter boundary and expose only the runtime roles implied by the contract package.</dependency-2>
      </dependency-contract-summaries>
      <verification-excerpt><![CDATA[
VerificationPlan / V-M-INFRA-COMPOSE / Gate-Phase-1:
- Module checks validate compose shape and smoke scaffolding, not full service boot, because runtime entrypoints are delivered in later phases.
- Success scenario: compose topology defines required services, env-file contracts, healthchecks, volumes, and startup ordering.
- Failure scenario: missing services, env contracts, or invalid compose wiring fail fast through config validation and smoke-script checks.
- Required marker: [InfraCompose][verifyLocalStack][BLOCK_VERIFY_LOCAL_STACK_HEALTH]
- Required assertion: Phase-1 validates topology shape only; compose-wide boot remains a later gate after service modules exist.
- Wave follow-up: exercise healthchecks and startup ordering under clean local state once API and worker entrypoints exist.
- Phase follow-up: run full smoke matrix before deleting the old single-process runtime path.
      ]]></verification-excerpt>
      <step-local-verification>
        <command-1>docker compose -f infra/docker-compose.yml config</command-1>
        <command-2>bash infra/scripts/compose-smoke.sh --check-config</command-2>
        <evidence-1>Compose shape covers postgres, redis, minio, api, worker-transcription, worker-report, worker-deep-research, web, telegram-bot, and mcp-server with explicit env-file and volume expectations.</evidence-1>
        <evidence-2>Runtime boot is not claimed in this phase; only deterministic config validation and smoke scaffolding are required before Phase-2 implementation starts.</evidence-2>
      </step-local-verification>
      <expected-graph-delta-fields>
        <field-1>imports: no module-import changes are expected outside the compose-owned runtime boundary.</field-1>
        <field-2>exports: confirm `export-composeStack` once the compose surface and smoke script exist.</field-2>
        <field-3>annotations: refine only runtime-topology annotations that become real and stable after this packet.</field-3>
        <field-4>CrossLinks: preserve existing runtime `runs` links; do not broaden ownership across business modules.</field-4>
      </expected-graph-delta-fields>
      <expected-verification-delta-fields>
        <field-1>test-files: define concrete compose config and smoke-script coverage under `infra/`.</field-1>
        <field-2>module-checks: preserve `docker compose -f infra/docker-compose.yml config` and the smoke-script config check as the narrow authoritative commands for this phase.</field-2>
        <field-3>required-log-markers: preserve `[InfraCompose][verifyLocalStack][BLOCK_VERIFY_LOCAL_STACK_HEALTH]` for the topology verification path.</field-3>
        <field-4>follow-up-checks: wave follow-up is live healthcheck exercise once service entrypoints exist; phase follow-up is full compose smoke before cutover.</field-4>
      </expected-verification-delta-fields>
      <notes>
        <note-1>This packet unblocks the next session by making the next executable target explicit in the execution layer.</note-1>
        <note-2>The compose module should centralize env and service wiring decisions so later module sessions do not fork local runtime assumptions.</note-2>
      </notes>
    </ExecutionPacket>

    <ExecutionPacket packet-id="M-API-STORAGE-wave-2" module="M-API-STORAGE" phase="Phase-2" step="1" verification-ref="V-M-API-STORAGE">
      <module-id>M-API-STORAGE</module-id>
      <module-name>ApiStorage</module-name>
      <purpose>Implement the first control-plane persistence boundary that makes PostgreSQL authoritative, MinIO durable, and artifact resolution plus webhook-delivery state reproducible for later job, events, and HTTP steps.</purpose>
      <write-scope>
        <file-1>apps/api/internal/storage/*.go</file-1>
        <file-2>apps/api/internal/storage/*_test.go</file-2>
        <file-3>apps/api/internal/storage/migrations/*.sql</file-3>
        <file-4>apps/api/internal/storage/testdata/*</file-4>
        <file-5>apps/api/go.mod</file-5>
        <file-6>apps/api/go.sum</file-6>
      </write-scope>
      <write-scope-notes>
        <note-1>Keep this step inside storage, migrations, and storage-local tests only.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not pull queue publishing, HTTP route logic, or job business rules into the storage package.</note-2>
        <note-3>Touch `apps/api/go.mod` and `apps/api/go.sum` only when concrete PostgreSQL or MinIO adapters need new package dependencies for storage-owned runtime wiring.</note-3>
        <note-4>Migration filenames must use zero-padded semantic snake_case names; phase-only labels are not acceptable for storage-owned schema history.</note-4>
      </write-scope-notes>
      <contract-excerpt><![CDATA[
DevelopmentPlan / M-API-STORAGE:
- Purpose: own PostgreSQL persistence, MinIO access, presigned URL resolution, and durable webhook-delivery records.
- Scope: SQL persistence, authoritative execution-claim state, MinIO object IO, presigned URL generation, source and artifact lifecycle checks, and durable delivery bookkeeping.
- Links: M-API-STORAGE, V-M-API-STORAGE, DF-001, DF-003, DF-006, DF-007.
- Note: `job_submissions` and `webhook_deliveries` are mandatory early tables, not optional polish.

PersistentModel + StorageContract + MigrationMapping:
- Storage step owns `job_submissions`, `sources`, `source_sets`, `source_set_items`, `jobs`, `job_executions`, `job_artifacts`, `job_events`, and `webhook_deliveries`.
- InternalWorkerContract depends on authoritative `execution_id` state across claim, progress, artifacts, finalize, and cancel-check; storage owns that persistence boundary and it must not be inferred from `jobs.started_at` alone.
- Enforce canonical rules for multi-file idempotent submissions, source/object-key constraints, ordered source sets, job lineage columns, artifact uniqueness, append-only job events, and durable webhook-delivery retry state.
- MinIO buckets are `sources` and `artifacts`; clients never upload directly to MinIO in v1, and presigned download links are generated by the API at read time using the public endpoint configured for browser access.
- `src/telegram_transcriber_bot/service.py` orchestration metadata is replaced by PostgreSQL, MinIO, and Redis-backed infrastructure in the new control plane.

ImplementationOrder / Phase-2 step-1:
- Add PostgreSQL migrations for sources, jobs, job_executions, job_artifacts, job_events, job_submissions, and webhook_deliveries.
- Add MinIO integration and presigned artifact resolution assumptions before queue, jobs, events, and HTTP build on top.
      ]]></contract-excerpt>
      <graph-entry-excerpt><![CDATA[
KnowledgeGraph / M-API-STORAGE:
- Path: apps/api/internal/storage
- Depends: M-CONTRACTS
- Verification ref: V-M-API-STORAGE
- Purpose: persist source metadata, jobs, execution claims, artifacts, events, and webhook-delivery records while generating presigned artifact links.
- Public annotations already expected in the graph:
  - export-persistSource
  - export-listJobs
  - export-getSourceSet
  - export-listOrderedSources
  - export-listArtifactsByJob
  - export-listChildJobs
  - export-listJobEvents
  - export-upsertArtifacts
  - export-claimJobExecution
  - export-getActiveJobExecution
  - export-finishJobExecution
  - export-resolveArtifact
  - type-JobSubmission
  - type-JobExecutionRecord
  - type-WebhookDelivery

Existing CrossLinks:
- M-API-JOBS -> M-API-STORAGE relation="persists-through"
- M-API-STORAGE -> M-API-JOBS relation="stores-state-for"
      ]]></graph-entry-excerpt>
      <dependency-contract-summaries>
        <dependency-1 module="M-CONTRACTS">Consume the frozen delivery strategy, artifact resolution, job snapshot, error envelope, and enum surfaces. Storage must not re-invent public shapes or drift from canonical enum values.</dependency-1>
        <dependency-2 module="M-API-JOBS-and-M-API-EVENTS">M-API-JOBS and M-API-EVENTS consume this storage surface next. Keep storage public methods narrow and persistence-oriented so the next steps reuse source-set and lineage state instead of embedding duplicate table logic elsewhere.</dependency-2>
      </dependency-contract-summaries>
      <verification-excerpt><![CDATA[
VerificationPlan / TestingStrategy / V-M-API-STORAGE / Gate-Phase-2:
- Module check: go test ./... -run ApiStorage
- Success scenario: source rows, source sets, jobs, artifacts, events, and webhook deliveries persist with correct lineage and constraints.
- Success scenario: combined transcription persistence creates one ordered source set plus ordered source_set_items and one job bound to that source set.
- Failure scenario: artifact resolution fails cleanly when object store or DB is unavailable.
- Required marker: [ApiStorage][persistJob][BLOCK_PERSIST_JOB_AND_ARTIFACT]
- Required assertions:
  - successful artifact uploads create DB rows only after object persistence succeeds;
  - internal worker execution ids remain authoritative and storage-backed rather than route-local or in-memory only.
- Wave follow-up: run migration application and rollback smoke checks, including the authoritative execution-claim path.
- Phase follow-up: presigned artifact URL validation passed on 2026-04-23 against the compose MinIO container and host browser path; returned download links use the public endpoint instead of Docker-internal service DNS.
- Phase gate evidence: DB migrations apply cleanly and the next control-plane steps return canonical envelopes built on this storage layer.
      ]]></verification-excerpt>
      <step-local-verification>
        <command-1>go test ./... -run ApiStorage</command-1>
        <command-2>Migration application and rollback smoke checks for the Phase-2 schema set.</command-2>
        <evidence-1>All required Phase-2 tables and constraints exist with the lossless PersistentModel semantics preserved, including ordered source sets for combined transcription.</evidence-1>
        <evidence-2>Presigned artifact resolution stays ephemeral and API-owned; object-store or DB outages surface deterministic storage failures instead of partial DB success.</evidence-2>
      </step-local-verification>
      <expected-graph-delta-fields>
        <field-1>imports: M-CONTRACTS only, plus internal storage helpers that stay inside the same module boundary.</field-1>
        <field-2>exports: confirm `export-persistSource`, `export-resolveArtifact`, and any stable persistence-facing helpers that become public to M-API-JOBS or M-API-EVENTS.</field-2>
        <field-3>annotations: refine only storage-owned public types and functions backed by real code, especially job submission and webhook delivery state.</field-3>
        <field-4>CrossLinks: preserve the existing M-API-JOBS storage links; add no new public cross-links unless a real storage-facing dependency becomes explicit in code.</field-4>
      </expected-graph-delta-fields>
      <expected-verification-delta-fields>
        <field-1>test-files: add migration, MinIO, and persistence tests under `apps/api/internal/storage/*_test.go` and storage-local fixtures.</field-1>
        <field-2>module-checks: preserve `go test ./... -run ApiStorage` and add the concrete migration smoke command chosen by the implementation.</field-2>
        <field-3>required-log-markers: preserve `[ApiStorage][persistJob][BLOCK_PERSIST_JOB_AND_ARTIFACT]` for the critical persistence path.</field-3>
        <field-4>follow-up-checks: wave follow-up is migration smoke plus execution-claim authority proof; phase follow-up is real MinIO validation and Phase-2 route checks that depend on this storage layer.</field-4>
      </expected-verification-delta-fields>
      <notes>
        <note-1>Create artifact rows only after MinIO object writes succeed.</note-1>
        <note-2>Presigned URLs are generated at read time; job snapshots and artifact metadata remain available even when URLs expire.</note-2>
        <note-3>YouTube sources may exist as DB rows without MinIO source objects in v1, but uploaded and Telegram sources require object keys.</note-3>
        <note-4>Use semantic migration filenames such as `0001_job_control_plane_foundation.sql`; do not encode packet or phase names into the filename.</note-4>
      </notes>
    </ExecutionPacket>

    <ExecutionPacket packet-id="M-API-QUEUE-wave-2" module="M-API-QUEUE" phase="Phase-2" step="2" verification-ref="V-M-API-QUEUE">
      <module-id>M-API-QUEUE</module-id>
      <module-name>ApiQueue</module-name>
      <purpose>Introduce the typed asynq publishing surface for Phase-2 without leaking business semantics into transport concerns.</purpose>
      <write-scope>
        <file-1>apps/api/internal/queue/*.go</file-1>
        <file-2>apps/api/internal/queue/*_test.go</file-2>
        <file-3>apps/api/internal/queue/testdata/*</file-3>
      </write-scope>
      <write-scope-notes>
        <note-1>Keep this step in queue publishing and queue-local tests only.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not move job lifecycle rules, storage writes, or worker logic into this package.</note-2>
      </write-scope-notes>
      <contract-excerpt><![CDATA[
DevelopmentPlan / M-API-QUEUE:
- Purpose: publish typed asynq tasks and encode queue-level retry and timeout defaults without owning business semantics.
- Scope: task type mapping, payload shaping, timeout policy, max retry settings, and SkipRetry classification.
- Links: M-API-QUEUE, V-M-API-QUEUE, DF-001, DF-004, DF-005, DF-006.
- Note: business-visible retry remains API-owned even though asynq performs transport-level retries.

QueueContract:
- Queue names and task types are frozen:
  - transcription -> job:transcription.run (max-retry 3, timeout 2h)
  - report -> job:report.run (max-retry 2, timeout 45m)
  - deep_research -> job:deep_research.run (max-retry 2, timeout 2h)
- Minimal payload is `job_id` plus attempt number. Full mutable job metadata must not be placed in asynq payloads.
- Deterministic business failures must use SkipRetry, including terminal claim rejection, authoritative cancel, missing parent artifact, invalid request data, and terminal model or pipeline failures.

ImplementationOrder / Phase-2 step-2:
- Add Redis queue producer through asynq by job type before job orchestration wires the queue into the business layer.
      ]]></contract-excerpt>
      <graph-entry-excerpt><![CDATA[
KnowledgeGraph / M-API-QUEUE:
- Path: apps/api/internal/queue
- Depends: M-CONTRACTS, M-API-JOBS
- Verification ref: V-M-API-QUEUE
- Purpose: bridge job creation and background execution through asynq queues and retry policies.
- Public annotations already expected in the graph:
  - export-enqueueJob

Existing CrossLinks:
- M-API-JOBS -> M-API-QUEUE relation="enqueues-through"
- M-API-QUEUE -> M-API-JOBS relation="accepts-work-from"
      ]]></graph-entry-excerpt>
      <dependency-contract-summaries>
        <dependency-1 module="M-CONTRACTS">Consume the frozen job types, statuses, and error semantics so queue payloads remain canonical and transport-only.</dependency-1>
        <dependency-2 module="M-API-JOBS-next-step">Implementation order puts queue before jobs. Keep the queue surface narrow and transport-oriented so Phase-2 step-3 can call it without forcing business semantics into the queue layer.</dependency-2>
      </dependency-contract-summaries>
      <verification-excerpt><![CDATA[
VerificationPlan / TestingStrategy / V-M-API-QUEUE / Gate-Phase-2:
- Module check: go test ./... -run ApiQueue
- Success scenario: jobs enqueue with correct task types, payloads, retries, and timeouts.
- Failure scenario: deterministic business failures use SkipRetry rather than repeating indefinitely.
- Required marker: [ApiQueue][enqueue][BLOCK_ENQUEUE_JOB]
- Required assertion: queue payload must not contain full mutable job metadata.
- Wave follow-up: run queue smoke checks against Redis and asynq inspector.
- Phase follow-up: verify queue behavior under cancel and dependency outage scenarios.
- Phase gate evidence: Phase-2 needs an enqueueable control plane before worker extraction starts.
      ]]></verification-excerpt>
      <step-local-verification>
        <command-1>go test ./... -run ApiQueue</command-1>
        <command-2>Queue smoke checks against Redis for task type, retry, timeout, and SkipRetry behavior.</command-2>
        <evidence-1>Only `job_id` and attempt metadata enter task payloads; mutable snapshots remain in PostgreSQL and are re-read through storage or jobs logic.</evidence-1>
        <evidence-2>Deterministic business failures produce SkipRetry rather than blind queue repetition.</evidence-2>
      </step-local-verification>
      <expected-graph-delta-fields>
        <field-1>imports: M-CONTRACTS only during the queue step itself; do not introduce direct Redis-facing dependencies into unrelated modules through the queue package.</field-1>
        <field-2>exports: confirm the stable enqueue entrypoint and any queue-type constants that become public to M-API-JOBS.</field-2>
        <field-3>annotations: refine only transport-facing queue annotations backed by real code.</field-3>
        <field-4>CrossLinks: preserve the existing M-API-JOBS and M-API-QUEUE relationship; do not create new public links unless a real public queue facade emerges.</field-4>
      </expected-graph-delta-fields>
      <expected-verification-delta-fields>
        <field-1>test-files: add queue payload, retry-policy, and SkipRetry tests under `apps/api/internal/queue/*_test.go`.</field-1>
        <field-2>module-checks: preserve `go test ./... -run ApiQueue` and add the concrete Redis queue smoke command chosen by implementation.</field-2>
        <field-3>required-log-markers: preserve `[ApiQueue][enqueue][BLOCK_ENQUEUE_JOB]` for the authoritative enqueue path.</field-3>
        <field-4>follow-up-checks: wave follow-up is queue smoke against Redis; phase follow-up is cancel and outage behavior once jobs and events are wired.</field-4>
      </expected-verification-delta-fields>
      <notes>
        <note-1>Transport retry is not business retry. Retry-as-new-job stays API-owned.</note-1>
        <note-2>Queue payloads should be stable enough for workers but intentionally too small to become an alternate source of truth.</note-2>
      </notes>
    </ExecutionPacket>

    <ExecutionPacket packet-id="M-API-JOBS-wave-2" module="M-API-JOBS" phase="Phase-2" step="3" verification-ref="V-M-API-JOBS">
      <module-id>M-API-JOBS</module-id>
      <module-name>ApiJobs</module-name>
      <purpose>Centralize Phase-2 business invariants so create, child reuse, cancel, retry, and lineage logic stay in one authoritative control-plane module.</purpose>
      <write-scope>
        <file-1>apps/api/internal/jobs/*.go</file-1>
        <file-2>apps/api/internal/jobs/*_test.go</file-2>
        <file-3>apps/api/internal/jobs/testdata/*</file-3>
      </write-scope>
      <write-scope-notes>
        <note-1>Keep this step inside the jobs package and jobs-local tests only.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not re-implement storage schema logic, queue transport policy, or WebSocket and webhook delivery machinery inside jobs.</note-2>
      </write-scope-notes>
      <contract-excerpt><![CDATA[
DevelopmentPlan / M-API-JOBS:
- Purpose: enforce delivery strategy, idempotency, job lineage, child reuse, cancel, retry, and terminal-state invariants.
- Scope: root job creation, child-job creation, state transitions, version increments, retry lineage, cancel semantics, and idempotency enforcement.
- Links: M-API-JOBS, V-M-API-JOBS, DF-001, DF-002, DF-004, DF-005, DF-006, DF-007.
- Note: workers must never bypass this module's transition rules.

PublicApiContract + RetryPolicy + CancellationPolicy + PersistentModel:
- Create endpoints support optional Idempotency-Key; equivalent request plus same key returns the original accepted response.
- The existing upload endpoint preserves one-file-to-one-job behavior; combined upload creates one job bound to one ordered source set.
- Create-child behavior is stronger than idempotency: if a canonical child already exists, return it even without an idempotency key.
- Retry is intentionally non-idempotent and creates a new row linked by `retry_of_job_id`; historical rows stay immutable.
- Cancel may finalize queued jobs directly as canceled, or set `cancel_requested` for running jobs; terminal jobs return unchanged.
- Persistent model rules freeze root, parent, retry, source-set, delivery, progress, and child uniqueness semantics.

ImplementationOrder / Phase-2 step-3:
- Implement job creation, child reuse, cancel, retry, and lineage rules after storage and queue primitives exist but before event and HTTP adapters close the public surface.
      ]]></contract-excerpt>
      <graph-entry-excerpt><![CDATA[
KnowledgeGraph / M-API-JOBS:
- Path: apps/api/internal/jobs
- Depends: M-CONTRACTS, M-API-STORAGE, M-API-QUEUE, M-API-EVENTS
- Verification ref: V-M-API-JOBS
- Purpose: own job creation, lineage, status transitions, child-job reuse, retry, and cancel semantics.
- Public annotations already expected in the graph:
  - export-createJob
  - export-transitionJob
  - type-JobLineage
  - type-CombinedTranscriptionJob

Existing CrossLinks:
- M-API-JOBS -> M-API-STORAGE relation="persists-through"
- M-API-JOBS -> M-API-QUEUE relation="enqueues-through"
- M-API-JOBS -> M-API-EVENTS relation="emits-through"
- M-API-JOBS -> M-API-HTTP relation="served-through"
      ]]></graph-entry-excerpt>
      <dependency-contract-summaries>
        <dependency-1 module="M-CONTRACTS">Consume the frozen request, snapshot, error, delivery, cancel, retry, and child-create contract semantics without redefining them in the jobs package.</dependency-1>
        <dependency-2 module="M-API-STORAGE">Use storage as the only authoritative read and write path for submissions, sources, source sets, jobs, artifacts, events, and delivery state.</dependency-2>
        <dependency-3 module="M-API-QUEUE">Queue publishing must stay transport-only. Jobs decides if and when enqueue happens, but must not leak mutable business state into queue payloads.</dependency-3>
        <dependency-4 module="M-API-EVENTS-next-step">Knowledge graph marks events as a dependency even though implementation order places jobs first. Keep jobs on a narrow event-emission seam and do not absorb WebSocket or webhook logic here.</dependency-4>
      </dependency-contract-summaries>
      <verification-excerpt><![CDATA[
VerificationPlan / TestingStrategy / V-M-API-JOBS / Gate-Phase-2:
- Module check: go test ./... -run ApiJobs
- Success scenario: create root and child jobs under correct lineage and delivery rules.
- Success scenario: combined transcription create produces one job from an ordered source set without breaking per-file upload semantics.
- Failure scenario: reject invalid transitions, malformed idempotency replays, and missing artifact prerequisites.
- Required marker: [ApiJobs][transitionJob][BLOCK_VALIDATE_AND_TRANSITION_JOB]
- Required assertion: retry must create a new row and never mutate terminal historical rows.
- Required assertion: combined transcription create must not fan out into one job per file.
- Testing strategy must prove canonical child reuse, retry-as-new-row, and polling remaining authoritative for webhook-configured jobs.
- Module readiness target: ready-after-state-transition-tests.
- Wave follow-up: exercise cancel and retry against real workers, not only storage mocks.
- Phase follow-up: cross-check child reuse and retry lineage in UI and Telegram flows.
      ]]></verification-excerpt>
      <step-local-verification>
        <command-1>go test ./... -run ApiJobs</command-1>
        <command-2>State-transition and lineage checks covering idempotent create, canonical child reuse, cancel, retry, and required-artifact validation.</command-2>
        <evidence-1>Retry creates a new lineage-linked row, never mutates historical rows, and does not copy artifacts or job events forward.</evidence-1>
        <evidence-2>Create-child requests reuse canonical children unless explicit retry is invoked, and combined transcription create preserves one-job semantics over ordered inputs.</evidence-2>
      </step-local-verification>
      <expected-graph-delta-fields>
        <field-1>imports: M-CONTRACTS, M-API-STORAGE, M-API-QUEUE, and the narrowest possible event-emission seam needed for the next M-API-EVENTS integration step.</field-1>
        <field-2>exports: confirm stable create, transition, cancel, retry, and child-job entrypoints that M-API-HTTP will route to.</field-2>
        <field-3>annotations: refine only job orchestration functions and types that become stable public module surface.</field-3>
        <field-4>CrossLinks: preserve the existing jobs-to-storage, jobs-to-queue, jobs-to-events, and jobs-to-http model; add nothing broader unless code makes a new public dependency explicit.</field-4>
      </expected-graph-delta-fields>
      <expected-verification-delta-fields>
        <field-1>test-files: add lineage, idempotency, child reuse, cancel, retry, and transition tests under `apps/api/internal/jobs/*_test.go`.</field-1>
        <field-2>module-checks: preserve `go test ./... -run ApiJobs` and record any focused state-transition command added during implementation.</field-2>
        <field-3>required-log-markers: preserve `[ApiJobs][transitionJob][BLOCK_VALIDATE_AND_TRANSITION_JOB]` for the authoritative transition path.</field-3>
        <field-4>follow-up-checks: wave follow-up is real worker integration; phase follow-up is cross-adapter lineage verification after Phase-5 adapters exist.</field-4>
      </expected-verification-delta-fields>
      <notes>
        <note-1>Create-child semantics are stronger than idempotency and should not be reinterpreted as "always create new."</note-1>
        <note-2>Workers, adapters, and HTTP handlers must route through jobs rather than mutating job rows directly.</note-2>
        <note-3>Do not implement retry by mutating a finished job row.</note-3>
      </notes>
    </ExecutionPacket>

    <ExecutionPacket packet-id="M-API-EVENTS-wave-2" module="M-API-EVENTS" phase="Phase-2" step="4" verification-ref="V-M-API-EVENTS">
      <module-id>M-API-EVENTS</module-id>
      <module-name>ApiEvents</module-name>
      <purpose>Make versioned job events durable and fanout-capable without turning WebSocket or webhook into a stronger source of truth than polling.</purpose>
      <write-scope>
        <file-1>apps/api/internal/ws/*.go</file-1>
        <file-2>apps/api/internal/ws/*_test.go</file-2>
        <file-3>apps/api/internal/ws/testdata/*</file-3>
      </write-scope>
      <write-scope-notes>
        <note-1>Keep this step in event persistence, WebSocket fanout, webhook scheduling, and events-local tests only.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not create an alternate read model or route orchestration logic here.</note-2>
      </write-scope-notes>
      <contract-excerpt><![CDATA[
DevelopmentPlan / M-API-EVENTS:
- Purpose: emit authoritative job events to job timelines, WebSocket clients, and webhook deliveries.
- Scope: versioned event persistence, WebSocket fanout, webhook scheduling, and reconnect-safe event semantics.
- Links: M-API-EVENTS, V-M-API-EVENTS, DF-003.
- Note: WebSocket is a low-latency UI channel; polling remains the correctness path.

PersistentModel + WebSocketContract + PublicApiContract webhook delivery:
- `job_events` is append-only, one row per job version.
- `webhook_deliveries` persists bounded retry state across API restarts and references `job_events`, not mutable job rows.
- Webhook delivery is best-effort with bounded retry and durable state.
- WebSocket clients must reconcile with REST on reconnect or version gap; polling remains authoritative.

ImplementationOrder / Phase-2 step-4:
- Implement job events, WebSocket fanout, and persisted webhook delivery scheduling after the jobs module owns authoritative transitions.
      ]]></contract-excerpt>
      <graph-entry-excerpt><![CDATA[
KnowledgeGraph / M-API-EVENTS:
- Path: apps/api/internal/ws
- Depends: M-CONTRACTS, M-API-STORAGE
- Verification ref: V-M-API-EVENTS
- Purpose: emit timeline, WebSocket, and webhook events from authoritative job transitions.
- Public annotations already expected in the graph:
  - export-broadcastEvent
  - export-scheduleWebhook
  - type-JobEventEnvelope

Existing CrossLinks:
- M-API-JOBS -> M-API-EVENTS relation="emits-through"
- M-API-EVENTS -> M-API-JOBS relation="observes-transitions-from"
      ]]></graph-entry-excerpt>
      <dependency-contract-summaries>
        <dependency-1 module="M-CONTRACTS">Consume the canonical WebSocket event envelope, webhook fields, delivery semantics, and polling-truth rule without redefining them inside the events module.</dependency-1>
        <dependency-2 module="M-API-STORAGE">Persist append-only event rows and durable webhook-delivery rows through the authoritative storage layer.</dependency-2>
        <dependency-3 module="M-API-JOBS">Observe authoritative transitions from jobs and emit versioned events from those transitions rather than from speculative route or worker state.</dependency-3>
      </dependency-contract-summaries>
      <verification-excerpt><![CDATA[
VerificationPlan / TestingStrategy / V-M-API-EVENTS / Gate-Phase-2:
- Module check: go test ./... -run ApiEvents
- Success scenario: versioned job events emit to timeline, WebSocket, and webhook delivery persistence.
- Failure scenario: webhook retries back off and persist state across restarts until delivered or dead.
- Required marker: [ApiEvents][emitJobEvent][BLOCK_EMIT_VERSIONED_EVENT]
- Required assertion: polling must remain authoritative even when WebSocket or webhook delivery succeeds.
- Module readiness target: caution, because webhook retry and WebSocket consistency are review-heavy until live integration checks exist.
- Wave follow-up: simulate network failure and 5xx webhook responses.
- Phase follow-up: verify UI reconnect behavior after forced WebSocket disconnect.
- Phase gate evidence: WebSocket and webhook delivery persistence are wired from versioned events before Phase-2 closes.
      ]]></verification-excerpt>
      <step-local-verification>
        <command-1>go test ./... -run ApiEvents</command-1>
        <command-2>Webhook retry and WebSocket reconnect simulations covering network failure, timeout, 5xx, and version-gap recovery.</command-2>
        <evidence-1>One job version maps to one persisted event row, and webhook delivery state survives API restarts.</evidence-1>
        <evidence-2>WebSocket fast-path behavior never suppresses the need for REST reconciliation on reconnect or version gaps.</evidence-2>
      </step-local-verification>
      <expected-graph-delta-fields>
        <field-1>imports: M-CONTRACTS and M-API-STORAGE, plus the narrow jobs-facing event trigger surface actually needed in code.</field-1>
        <field-2>exports: confirm stable broadcast and webhook scheduling entrypoints plus the public event-envelope type.</field-2>
        <field-3>annotations: refine only event-emission and webhook-delivery annotations that become public module surface.</field-3>
        <field-4>CrossLinks: preserve the existing jobs and events relationship; add no new public links unless HTTP or another module directly consumes events through a stable public contract.</field-4>
      </expected-graph-delta-fields>
      <expected-verification-delta-fields>
        <field-1>test-files: add timeline, WebSocket, webhook retry, and restart-survival tests under `apps/api/internal/ws/*_test.go`.</field-1>
        <field-2>module-checks: preserve `go test ./... -run ApiEvents` and record the concrete webhook-failure and reconnect smoke commands chosen by implementation.</field-2>
        <field-3>required-log-markers: preserve `[ApiEvents][emitJobEvent][BLOCK_EMIT_VERSIONED_EVENT]` for the event emission path.</field-3>
        <field-4>follow-up-checks: wave follow-up is simulated delivery failure; phase follow-up is UI reconnect verification and broader Phase-2 integration.</field-4>
      </expected-verification-delta-fields>
      <notes>
        <note-1>Webhook deliveries reference immutable event rows rather than mutable job rows.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not let WebSocket become a hidden authoritative read model.</note-2>
      </notes>
    </ExecutionPacket>

    <ExecutionPacket packet-id="M-API-HTTP-wave-2" module="M-API-HTTP" phase="Phase-2" step="5" verification-ref="V-M-API-HTTP">
      <module-id>M-API-HTTP</module-id>
      <module-name>ApiHttp</module-name>
      <purpose>Bind the frozen public and internal HTTP surface to the completed Phase-2 control-plane modules without moving business logic out of jobs, storage, queue, or events.</purpose>
      <write-scope>
        <file-1>apps/api/internal/api/*.go</file-1>
        <file-2>apps/api/internal/api/*_test.go</file-2>
        <file-3>apps/api/internal/api/testdata/*</file-3>
      </write-scope>
      <write-scope-notes>
        <note-1>Keep this step in HTTP handlers, request shaping, WebSocket session entry, and API-local tests only.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not move orchestration, persistence, queue, or event logic into the route layer.</note-2>
      </write-scope-notes>
      <contract-excerpt><![CDATA[
DevelopmentPlan / M-API-HTTP:
- Purpose: expose public and internal HTTP routes that bind incoming requests to API job orchestration logic.
- Scope: multipart upload handling, JSON request validation, route binding, error envelopes, and WebSocket session entry.
- Links: M-API-HTTP, V-M-API-HTTP, DF-001, DF-002, DF-003, DF-004, DF-005, DF-006, DF-007.
- Note: public routes and internal worker routes should remain explicit rather than merged by convention.

PublicApiContract + InternalWorkerContract + ExecutionRules:
- Public routes cover per-file multipart upload, combined multipart upload, URL create, get, list, report child create, deep-research child create, cancel, retry, artifact resolve, and events.
- Internal worker routes cover claim, progress, artifacts, finalize, and cancel-check.
- Create endpoints support optional Idempotency-Key, delivery strategy, webhook URL validation, and a recommended 1 GiB request limit.
- Error envelopes use stable `error.code`, `error.message`, and `error.details`.
- Do not merge public client routes with internal worker-control routes, and do not treat WebSocket as the only status mechanism.

ImplementationOrder / Phase-2 step-5:
- Expose public and internal worker routes only after storage, queue, jobs, and events surfaces are already in place.
      ]]></contract-excerpt>
      <graph-entry-excerpt><![CDATA[
KnowledgeGraph / M-API-HTTP:
- Path: apps/api/internal/api
- Depends: M-CONTRACTS, M-API-JOBS, M-API-STORAGE, M-API-QUEUE, M-API-EVENTS
- Verification ref: V-M-API-HTTP
- Purpose: expose create, list, get, cancel, retry, artifact, event, and internal worker endpoints for the control plane.
- Public annotations already expected in the graph:
  - export-registerRoutes
  - export-validateRequest
  - export-buildRuntimeDependencies

Existing CrossLinks:
- M-CONTRACTS -> M-API-HTTP relation="defines-public-contracts-for"
- M-API-HTTP -> M-CONTRACTS relation="depends-on-contracts-from"
- M-API-HTTP -> M-API-JOBS relation="routes-to"
- M-API-HTTP -> M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION relation="provides-internal-control-plane-to"
- M-API-HTTP -> M-WORKER-REPORT relation="provides-internal-control-plane-to"
- M-API-HTTP -> M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH relation="provides-internal-control-plane-to"
      ]]></graph-entry-excerpt>
      <dependency-contract-summaries>
        <dependency-1 module="M-CONTRACTS">HTTP must shape requests and responses exactly to the frozen public and internal contract surface, including multipart rules, webhook validation, event envelopes, and error codes.</dependency-1>
        <dependency-2 module="M-API-JOBS">Route handlers delegate all business orchestration, lineage, cancel, retry, and child-create rules to jobs.</dependency-2>
        <dependency-3 module="M-API-STORAGE">Artifact resolution and job inspection rely on storage-backed authoritative state and presigned-link semantics.</dependency-3>
        <dependency-4 module="M-API-EVENTS">WebSocket session entry and event timeline routes rely on the versioned events module while preserving polling as the truth path.</dependency-4>
        <dependency-5 module="M-API-QUEUE-graph-edge">Knowledge graph includes queue in the HTTP dependency set. Keep any queue awareness indirect through jobs and do not create direct Redis-facing route logic.</dependency-5>
      </dependency-contract-summaries>
      <verification-excerpt><![CDATA[
VerificationPlan / TestingStrategy / V-M-API-HTTP / Gate-Phase-2:
- Module check: go test ./... -run ApiHttp
- Success scenario: public endpoints shape accepted requests and responses according to the canonical contract, including the separate combined upload route.
- Success scenario: local Web UI browser origins receive CORS headers for REST polling and action routes.
- Failure scenario: invalid UUIDs, missing webhook URLs, oversized uploads, and unsupported source URLs return stable error envelopes.
- Required marker: [ApiHttp][validateRequest][BLOCK_VALIDATE_REQUEST_AND_SHAPE_RESPONSE]
- Required assertion: internal worker endpoints must not be confused with public client endpoints.
- Wave follow-up: run API handler tests with real multipart and JSON fixtures for both per-file and combined upload routes.
- Phase follow-up: full route regression against generated SDKs and manual curl smoke checks.
- Phase gate evidence: core routes return canonical envelopes, and the full Go control plane can create, persist, enqueue, and inspect jobs using contract-compliant routes.
      ]]></verification-excerpt>
      <step-local-verification>
        <command-1>go test ./... -run ApiHttp</command-1>
        <command-2>Route-level per-file multipart, combined multipart, JSON, WebSocket, and internal worker fixture checks plus targeted manual curl smoke coverage.</command-2>
        <evidence-1>Public route outputs match the canonical job, artifact, event, and error envelopes from M-CONTRACTS.</evidence-1>
        <evidence-2>Internal worker-control routes stay explicit and do not leak into the public client surface.</evidence-2>
      </step-local-verification>
      <expected-graph-delta-fields>
        <field-1>imports: M-CONTRACTS, M-API-JOBS, M-API-STORAGE, and M-API-EVENTS, with any queue awareness remaining indirect through jobs unless code proves otherwise.</field-1>
        <field-2>exports: confirm stable route registration, request validation, and WebSocket entrypoints that become public module surface.</field-2>
        <field-3>annotations: refine only route-layer exports that stay stable and do not absorb business logic ownership.</field-3>
        <field-4>CrossLinks: preserve the current contract, jobs, and worker-facing route graph; add no broader ownership links from HTTP to storage, queue, or events unless real public code requires them.</field-4>
      </expected-graph-delta-fields>
      <expected-verification-delta-fields>
        <field-1>test-files: add multipart, JSON, error-envelope, event-route, WebSocket, and internal worker route tests under `apps/api/internal/api/*_test.go`.</field-1>
        <field-2>module-checks: preserve `go test ./... -run ApiHttp` and record any fixture-driven handler or curl smoke command added by the implementation.</field-2>
        <field-3>required-log-markers: preserve `[ApiHttp][validateRequest][BLOCK_VALIDATE_REQUEST_AND_SHAPE_RESPONSE]` for the route validation path.</field-3>
        <field-4>follow-up-checks: wave follow-up is real multipart plus JSON handler coverage; phase follow-up is broader route regression and SDK or manual consumer smoke checks.</field-4>
      </expected-verification-delta-fields>
      <notes>
        <note-1>HTTP binds contracts to modules; it does not become the place where business rules live.</note-1>
        <note-2>Keep public and internal worker routes explicit and independently testable.</note-2>
      </notes>
    </ExecutionPacket>

    <ExecutionPacket packet-id="M-WORKER-COMMON-wave-3" module="M-WORKER-COMMON" phase="Phase-3" step="1" verification-ref="V-M-WORKER-COMMON">
      <module-id>M-WORKER-COMMON</module-id>
      <module-name>WorkerCommon</module-name>
      <purpose>Extract the shared Python worker runtime layer so transcription, report, and deep-research workers all use one canonical internal API client, artifact-writing contract, and execution scaffold.</purpose>
      <packet-state>completed</packet-state>
      <completion-evidence>.venv/bin/python -m pytest workers/common/tests passed; shared API client, object-store adapter, and worker loop are consumed by all worker launcher packets.</completion-evidence>
      <write-scope>
        <file-1>workers/common/src/transcriber_workers_common/*.py</file-1>
        <file-2>workers/common/tests/*.py</file-2>
        <file-3>src/telegram_transcriber_bot/transcribers.py</file-3>
        <file-4>src/telegram_transcriber_bot/documents.py</file-4>
      </write-scope>
      <write-scope-notes>
        <note-1>Touch current monolith files only to extract reusable helper boundaries into `workers/common`; do not change Telegram UX or worker-specific orchestration here.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not broaden into `workers/transcription`, `workers/report`, `workers/deep-research`, `apps/api`, or adapter code in this packet.</note-2>
      </write-scope-notes>
      <contract-excerpt><![CDATA[
DevelopmentPlan / M-WORKER-COMMON:
- Purpose: provide shared Python helpers for claim, progress, finalize calls, storage utilities, and execution scaffolding.
- Scope: internal API client helpers, artifact upload helpers, typed execution context parsing, and common cancellation probes.
- Links: M-WORKER-COMMON, V-M-WORKER-COMMON, DF-001, DF-004, DF-005, DF-006, DF-007.
- Error: internal_api_unavailable.

MigrationMapping + Wave-3:
- `src/telegram_transcriber_bot/transcribers.py` maps into `workers/common/src/transcriber_workers_common/transcribers.py` plus worker-specific transcription code.
- `src/telegram_transcriber_bot/documents.py` maps into `workers/common/src/transcriber_workers_common/documents.py`.
- Phase-3 step-1 creates the shared Python worker API and storage helpers before any worker-specific run loop is implemented.
      ]]></contract-excerpt>
      <graph-entry-excerpt><![CDATA[
KnowledgeGraph / M-WORKER-COMMON:
- Path: workers/common
- Depends: M-CONTRACTS
- Verification ref: V-M-WORKER-COMMON
- Purpose: host shared Python execution utilities reused by transcription, report, and deep-research workers.
- Public annotations already expected in the graph:
  - export-apiClient
  - export-artifactWriters

Existing CrossLinks:
- M-WORKER-COMMON -> M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION relation="provides-shared-worker-runtime-to"
- M-WORKER-COMMON -> M-WORKER-REPORT relation="provides-shared-worker-runtime-to"
- M-WORKER-COMMON -> M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH relation="provides-shared-worker-runtime-to"
      ]]></graph-entry-excerpt>
      <dependency-contract-summaries>
        <dependency-1 module="M-CONTRACTS">Shared helpers must shape claim, progress, artifact, finalize, and cancel-check payloads exactly to the frozen worker-control contracts.</dependency-1>
      </dependency-contract-summaries>
      <verification-excerpt><![CDATA[
VerificationPlan / V-M-WORKER-COMMON / Gate-Phase-3:
- Module check: .venv/bin/python -m pytest workers/common/tests
- Success scenario: shared worker API client and artifact helpers produce valid internal control-plane payloads.
- Failure scenario: internal API unavailability or malformed artifact payloads fail deterministically before worker-specific execution continues.
- Required marker: [WorkerCommon][callInternalApi][BLOCK_CALL_INTERNAL_CONTROL_PLANE]
- Runtime marker: [WorkerCommon][runWorkerLoop][BLOCK_RUN_WORKER_LOOP]
- Required assertions:
  - workers must not bypass internal control-plane contracts;
  - artifact helper output remains compatible with canonical finalize and artifact-registration DTOs.
- Wave follow-up: reuse these helpers across all worker implementations before diverging code paths appear.
- Phase follow-up: inspect DTO drift whenever contracts change.
      ]]></verification-excerpt>
      <step-local-verification>
        <command-1>.venv/bin/python -m pytest workers/common/tests</command-1>
        <command-2>Contract-shaped helper checks covering claim/progress/finalize payloads, artifact metadata writes, and deterministic internal API failure handling.</command-2>
        <evidence-1>Worker-common exposes one reusable API client and one reusable artifact-writer surface that later worker packets can consume without redefining DTO shapes.</evidence-1>
        <evidence-2>Current reusable transcription and document helpers move behind the shared worker boundary without changing end-user behavior in this packet.</evidence-2>
      </step-local-verification>
      <expected-graph-delta-fields>
        <field-1>imports: confirm the stable dependency on M-CONTRACTS and any worker-local helper imports that stay inside the shared package.</field-1>
        <field-2>exports: confirm stable shared worker API client and artifact-writer entrypoints.</field-2>
        <field-3>annotations: refine only shared helper exports that remain public to the worker layer.</field-3>
        <field-4>CrossLinks: preserve the shared-runtime links from M-WORKER-COMMON to the three worker modules.</field-4>
      </expected-graph-delta-fields>
      <expected-verification-delta-fields>
        <field-1>test-files: add concrete worker-common helper tests under `workers/common/tests`.</field-1>
        <field-2>module-checks: preserve the narrow pytest command for worker-common only.</field-2>
        <field-3>required-log-markers: preserve `[WorkerCommon][callInternalApi][BLOCK_CALL_INTERNAL_CONTROL_PLANE]`.</field-3>
        <field-4>follow-up-checks: worker-common is only done when later worker packets can consume it without redefining worker-control DTOs.</field-4>
      </expected-verification-delta-fields>
      <notes>
        <note-1>This packet exists to prevent three worker implementations from forking internal control-plane behavior.</note-1>
        <note-2>Keep private worker-specific logic out of worker-common; only shared runtime pieces belong here.</note-2>
      </notes>
    </ExecutionPacket>

    <ExecutionPacket packet-id="M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION-wave-3" module="M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION" phase="Phase-3" step="2" verification-ref="V-M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION">
      <module-id>M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION</module-id>
      <module-name>WorkerTranscription</module-name>
      <purpose>Move transcription execution into a dedicated worker that claims jobs through the API-owned control contract, preserves current transcript outputs, and handles ordered combined-media inputs deterministically.</purpose>
      <packet-state>completed</packet-state>
      <completion-evidence>.venv/bin/python -m pytest workers/transcription/tests passed; compose-ready transcription launcher exists and reuses WorkerCommon runtime.</completion-evidence>
      <write-scope>
        <file-1>workers/transcription/src/*.py</file-1>
        <file-2>workers/transcription/tests/*.py</file-2>
        <file-3>tests/test_transcribers.py</file-3>
        <file-4>tests/test_documents.py</file-4>
        <file-5>src/telegram_transcriber_bot/service.py</file-5>
      </write-scope>
      <write-scope-notes>
        <note-1>Touch `service.py` only to extract or detach source materialization and transcript orchestration into the worker shell.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not move report, deep-research, Telegram, or compose concerns into this packet.</note-2>
      </write-scope-notes>
      <contract-excerpt><![CDATA[
DevelopmentPlan / M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION:
- Purpose: reuse source extraction, YouTube resolution, faster-whisper, and document rendering to produce transcript artifacts.
- Scope: source materialization, subtitle fast path, Whisper fallback, transcript rendering, artifact upload, and terminal finalization.
- Links: M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION, V-M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION, DF-001, DF-002, DF-006, DF-007.
- Errors: source_fetch_failed, transcription_failed.

Wave-3 + DataFlows:
- Phase-3 step-2 implements the worker claim and run loop.
- Phase-3 step-3 preserves plain transcript, segmented markdown transcript, and transcript docx outputs.
- Phase-3 step-4 adds cancellation checks before and after long work.
- DF-001, DF-002, and DF-007 require ordered input handling, combined-media concatenation, and deterministic success finalization only after all required artifacts exist.
      ]]></contract-excerpt>
      <graph-entry-excerpt><![CDATA[
KnowledgeGraph / M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION:
- Path: workers/transcription
- Depends: M-WORKER-COMMON, M-CONTRACTS
- Verification ref: V-M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION
- Purpose: execute transcription jobs by reusing existing source materialization, faster-whisper, and transcript rendering logic.
- Public annotations already expected in the graph:
  - export-runTranscription
  - type-OrderedWorkerInput

Existing CrossLinks:
- M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION -> M-API-HTTP relation="claims-and-finalizes-through"
- M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION -> M-WORKER-COMMON relation="reuses-shared-worker-runtime-from"
      ]]></graph-entry-excerpt>
      <dependency-contract-summaries>
        <dependency-1 module="M-WORKER-COMMON">Transcription must reuse the shared worker API client, artifact writers, and execution scaffolding instead of redefining worker-control behavior locally.</dependency-1>
        <dependency-2 module="M-CONTRACTS">Claimed input shape, artifact registration, progress updates, and finalization must stay contract-compatible across single-file, URL, and combined-media flows.</dependency-2>
      </dependency-contract-summaries>
      <verification-excerpt><![CDATA[
VerificationPlan / V-M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION / Gate-Phase-3:
- Module check: .venv/bin/python -m pytest tests/test_transcribers.py tests/test_documents.py
- Success scenario: worker produces plain, segmented, and DOCX transcript artifacts from uploaded and YouTube sources.
- Failure scenario: unsupported URLs, empty transcripts, and downloader failures surface deterministic terminal errors.
- Success scenario: worker preserves ordering and emits one artifact set for combined multi-media transcription jobs.
- Required marker: [WorkerTranscription][runTranscription][BLOCK_EXECUTE_TRANSCRIPTION_PIPELINE]
- Required assertions:
  - success finalization must not happen before all required transcript artifacts exist;
  - when more than one ordered input exists, concatenation occurs before the final transcription pass and before success finalization.
- Wave follow-up: run end-to-end against real MinIO and internal API claim/finalize endpoints.
- Phase follow-up: replay current Telegram UX expectations using the thin adapter.
      ]]></verification-excerpt>
      <step-local-verification>
        <command-1>.venv/bin/python -m pytest tests/test_transcribers.py tests/test_documents.py</command-1>
        <command-2>.venv/bin/python -m pytest workers/transcription/tests</command-2>
        <evidence-1>The worker produces the preserved transcript artifact set and uses ordered-input concatenation only for combined transcription jobs.</evidence-1>
        <evidence-2>Cancellation and terminal-failure behavior are observable around the dedicated worker run loop rather than through Telegram-local orchestration.</evidence-2>
      </step-local-verification>
      <expected-graph-delta-fields>
        <field-1>imports: confirm stable dependencies on M-WORKER-COMMON and M-CONTRACTS, plus the API-facing control-plane edge already present in the graph.</field-1>
        <field-2>exports: confirm `export-runTranscription` and ordered-input type annotations.</field-2>
        <field-3>annotations: refine only the public worker entrypoint and ordered-input annotations that become stable under extraction.</field-3>
        <field-4>CrossLinks: preserve claims-and-finalizes-through HTTP and shared-runtime reuse links.</field-4>
      </expected-graph-delta-fields>
      <expected-verification-delta-fields>
        <field-1>test-files: keep current transcript and document regression tests while adding worker-specific tests under `workers/transcription/tests`.</field-1>
        <field-2>module-checks: preserve narrow pytest commands for transcription and document surfaces.</field-2>
        <field-3>required-log-markers: preserve `[WorkerTranscription][runTranscription][BLOCK_EXECUTE_TRANSCRIPTION_PIPELINE]`.</field-3>
        <field-4>follow-up-checks: end-to-end MinIO and API claim/finalize checks remain wave follow-up, not part of the extraction packet itself.</field-4>
      </expected-verification-delta-fields>
      <notes>
        <note-1>Do not re-implement ML behavior in Go or in the Telegram adapter.</note-1>
        <note-2>Keep packet scope on execution extraction and artifact preservation, not on downstream adapter parity.</note-2>
      </notes>
    </ExecutionPacket>

    <ExecutionPacket packet-id="M-WORKER-REPORT-wave-4" module="M-WORKER-REPORT" phase="Phase-4" step="1" verification-ref="V-M-WORKER-REPORT">
      <module-id>M-WORKER-REPORT</module-id>
      <module-name>WorkerReport</module-name>
      <purpose>Extract report generation into a dedicated worker that consumes transcript artifacts, executes `cglm`, preserves markdown plus DOCX outputs, and keeps subprocess cancellation under the API-owned job shell.</purpose>
      <packet-state>completed</packet-state>
      <completion-evidence>.venv/bin/python -m pytest workers/report/tests passed; compose-ready report launcher exists and reuses WorkerCommon runtime.</completion-evidence>
      <write-scope>
        <file-1>workers/report/src/*.py</file-1>
        <file-2>workers/report/tests/*.py</file-2>
        <file-3>tests/test_cglm_runner.py</file-3>
        <file-4>tests/test_cglm_runner_errors.py</file-4>
        <file-5>src/telegram_transcriber_bot/cglm_runner.py</file-5>
        <file-6>src/telegram_transcriber_bot/documents.py</file-6>
      </write-scope>
      <write-scope-notes>
        <note-1>Touch existing `cglm_runner.py` and report DOCX rendering only to move them into the report worker layer.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not broaden into API child-job rules or deep-research execution in this packet.</note-2>
      </write-scope-notes>
      <contract-excerpt><![CDATA[
DevelopmentPlan / M-WORKER-REPORT:
- Purpose: generate markdown and DOCX research reports from transcript artifacts using cglm.
- Scope: cglm command execution, subprocess lifecycle handling, report rendering, artifact upload, and terminal finalization.
- Links: M-WORKER-REPORT, V-M-WORKER-REPORT, DF-004, DF-006.
- Error: report_failed.

Wave-4 + MigrationMapping:
- `src/telegram_transcriber_bot/cglm_runner.py` maps into `workers/report/src`.
- Report DOCX generation is extracted from `src/telegram_transcriber_bot/documents.py`.
- Phase-4 step-1 is the report-worker extraction wave; API child-job validation remains a dependency and not an ownership change for this packet.
      ]]></contract-excerpt>
      <graph-entry-excerpt><![CDATA[
KnowledgeGraph / M-WORKER-REPORT:
- Path: workers/report
- Depends: M-WORKER-COMMON, M-CONTRACTS
- Verification ref: V-M-WORKER-REPORT
- Purpose: execute report jobs using `cglm` and report artifact rendering while preserving current report behavior.
- Public annotations already expected in the graph:
  - export-runReport

Existing CrossLinks:
- M-WORKER-REPORT -> M-API-HTTP relation="claims-and-finalizes-through"
- M-WORKER-REPORT -> M-WORKER-COMMON relation="reuses-shared-worker-runtime-from"
      ]]></graph-entry-excerpt>
      <dependency-contract-summaries>
        <dependency-1 module="M-WORKER-COMMON">Report execution must reuse shared claim/progress/finalize and artifact helper surfaces instead of inventing report-specific transport logic.</dependency-1>
        <dependency-2 module="M-CONTRACTS">Artifact registration, error reporting, and terminal worker finalization must stay aligned with the frozen worker-control DTOs.</dependency-2>
      </dependency-contract-summaries>
      <verification-excerpt><![CDATA[
VerificationPlan / V-M-WORKER-REPORT / Gate-Phase-4:
- Module check: .venv/bin/python -m pytest tests/test_cglm_runner.py tests/test_cglm_runner_errors.py
- Success scenario: report worker produces markdown and DOCX artifacts from transcript input.
- Failure scenario: missing binary, timeout, and non-zero exit are surfaced as deterministic worker failures.
- Required marker: [WorkerReport][runReport][BLOCK_EXECUTE_REPORT_PIPELINE]
- Required assertion: cancellation must terminate subprocess execution before finalizing `canceled`.
- Wave follow-up: validate report child reuse semantics through the API.
- Phase follow-up: run report-worker integration against real internal control-plane endpoints.
      ]]></verification-excerpt>
      <step-local-verification>
        <command-1>.venv/bin/python -m pytest tests/test_cglm_runner.py tests/test_cglm_runner_errors.py</command-1>
        <command-2>.venv/bin/python -m pytest workers/report/tests</command-2>
        <evidence-1>Report worker preserves markdown and DOCX outputs while running `cglm` behind the dedicated worker shell.</evidence-1>
        <evidence-2>Subprocess timeout, missing binary, non-zero exit, and cancel-aware handling are observable through the worker packet boundary.</evidence-2>
      </step-local-verification>
      <expected-graph-delta-fields>
        <field-1>imports: confirm stable dependencies on M-WORKER-COMMON and M-CONTRACTS.</field-1>
        <field-2>exports: confirm `export-runReport` as the public worker entrypoint.</field-2>
        <field-3>annotations: refine only stable report worker entrypoint annotations.</field-3>
        <field-4>CrossLinks: preserve HTTP control-plane and shared-runtime reuse links.</field-4>
      </expected-graph-delta-fields>
      <expected-verification-delta-fields>
        <field-1>test-files: preserve current cglm regression coverage while adding `workers/report/tests`.</field-1>
        <field-2>module-checks: keep the narrow report-focused pytest commands.</field-2>
        <field-3>required-log-markers: preserve `[WorkerReport][runReport][BLOCK_EXECUTE_REPORT_PIPELINE]`.</field-3>
        <field-4>follow-up-checks: API child reuse stays wave follow-up and real control-plane integration stays phase follow-up.</field-4>
      </expected-verification-delta-fields>
      <notes>
        <note-1>Report job creation remains API-owned; this packet only extracts the execution layer.</note-1>
        <note-2>Keep cglm subprocess semantics explicit and cancel-aware.</note-2>
      </notes>
    </ExecutionPacket>

    <ExecutionPacket packet-id="M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH-wave-4" module="M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH" phase="Phase-4" step="2" verification-ref="V-M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH">
      <module-id>M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH</module-id>
      <module-name>WorkerDeepResearch</module-name>
      <purpose>Extract the deep-research pipeline into a dedicated worker that preserves phase artifacts, final markdown output, optional execution logs, and deterministic terminal-failure handling.</purpose>
      <packet-state>completed</packet-state>
      <completion-evidence>.venv/bin/python -m pytest workers/deep-research/tests passed; compose-ready deep-research launcher exists and reuses WorkerCommon runtime.</completion-evidence>
      <write-scope>
        <file-1>workers/deep-research/src/*.py</file-1>
        <file-2>workers/deep-research/tests/*.py</file-2>
        <file-3>tests/test_deep_research.py</file-3>
        <file-4>src/telegram_transcriber_bot/deep_research.py</file-4>
      </write-scope>
      <write-scope-notes>
        <note-1>Touch the current deep-research pipeline only to move it into the dedicated worker shell with minimal rewrite.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not broaden into report worker internals or UI surfacing in this packet.</note-2>
      </write-scope-notes>
      <contract-excerpt><![CDATA[
DevelopmentPlan / M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH:
- Purpose: run the evidence-driven deep-research pipeline and persist the final markdown output plus optional execution logs.
- Scope: phase-driven deep-research execution, required artifact validation, optional log persistence, and terminal finalization.
- Links: M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH, V-M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH, DF-005, DF-006.
- Error: deep_research_failed.

Wave-4 + MigrationMapping:
- `src/telegram_transcriber_bot/deep_research.py` maps into `workers/deep-research/src`.
- The packet preserves the current multi-phase pipeline while adding worker-shell finalization, artifact persistence, and cancellation boundaries.
      ]]></contract-excerpt>
      <graph-entry-excerpt><![CDATA[
KnowledgeGraph / M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH:
- Path: workers/deep-research
- Depends: M-WORKER-COMMON, M-CONTRACTS
- Verification ref: V-M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH
- Purpose: execute deep-research jobs by reusing the current evidence-driven multi-phase pipeline.
- Public annotations already expected in the graph:
  - export-runDeepResearch

Existing CrossLinks:
- M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH -> M-API-HTTP relation="claims-and-finalizes-through"
- M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH -> M-WORKER-COMMON relation="reuses-shared-worker-runtime-from"
      ]]></graph-entry-excerpt>
      <dependency-contract-summaries>
        <dependency-1 module="M-WORKER-COMMON">Deep-research execution must reuse shared worker transport, artifact, and cancellation helpers.</dependency-1>
        <dependency-2 module="M-CONTRACTS">Worker finalization, optional execution-log registration, and terminal error shaping must remain contract-compatible.</dependency-2>
      </dependency-contract-summaries>
      <verification-excerpt><![CDATA[
VerificationPlan / V-M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH / Gate-Phase-4:
- Module check: .venv/bin/python -m pytest tests/test_deep_research.py
- Success scenario: deep-research worker preserves required phase artifacts and final markdown output.
- Failure scenario: pipeline timeouts, missing phase artifacts, and blocked writes surface deterministic failures.
- Required marker: [WorkerDeepResearch][runDeepResearch][BLOCK_EXECUTE_DEEP_RESEARCH_PIPELINE]
- Required assertion: terminal success must not be emitted if required deep-research outputs are missing.
- Wave follow-up: run integration against API-created deep-research child jobs.
- Phase follow-up: smoke-check deep-research runtime inside Docker Compose.
      ]]></verification-excerpt>
      <step-local-verification>
        <command-1>.venv/bin/python -m pytest tests/test_deep_research.py</command-1>
        <command-2>.venv/bin/python -m pytest workers/deep-research/tests</command-2>
        <evidence-1>Worker extraction preserves required deep-research phase artifacts and the final markdown contract before success finalization.</evidence-1>
        <evidence-2>Timeouts, missing phase outputs, and blocked writes are surfaced as deterministic worker failures instead of partial success.</evidence-2>
      </step-local-verification>
      <expected-graph-delta-fields>
        <field-1>imports: confirm stable dependencies on M-WORKER-COMMON and M-CONTRACTS.</field-1>
        <field-2>exports: confirm `export-runDeepResearch` as the stable public worker entrypoint.</field-2>
        <field-3>annotations: refine only stable deep-research worker entrypoints and public output annotations.</field-3>
        <field-4>CrossLinks: preserve HTTP control-plane and shared-runtime reuse links.</field-4>
      </expected-graph-delta-fields>
      <expected-verification-delta-fields>
        <field-1>test-files: preserve current deep-research regression coverage while adding `workers/deep-research/tests`.</field-1>
        <field-2>module-checks: keep narrow deep-research pytest commands.</field-2>
        <field-3>required-log-markers: preserve `[WorkerDeepResearch][runDeepResearch][BLOCK_EXECUTE_DEEP_RESEARCH_PIPELINE]`.</field-3>
        <field-4>follow-up-checks: API-created child-job integration and compose smoke remain later checks outside this extraction packet.</field-4>
      </expected-verification-delta-fields>
      <notes>
        <note-1>Do not collapse deep research into report or transcription worker ownership.</note-1>
        <note-2>Preserve the evidence-driven pipeline phases instead of rewriting them during extraction.</note-2>
      </notes>
    </ExecutionPacket>

    <ExecutionPacket packet-id="M-WEB-UI-app-shell-wave-5" module="M-WEB-UI" phase="Phase-5" step="0" verification-ref="V-M-WEB-UI">
      <module-id>M-WEB-UI</module-id>
      <module-name>WebUi</module-name>
      <purpose>Create the minimal `apps/web` application shell and app-local test harness required so the Web UI implementation packet can execute inside its declared source and test scope without broadening into API or adapter work.</purpose>
      <write-scope>
        <file-1>apps/web/package.json</file-1>
        <file-2>apps/web/pnpm-lock.yaml</file-2>
        <file-3>apps/web/index.html</file-3>
        <file-4>apps/web/.env.example</file-4>
        <file-5>apps/web/tsconfig*.json</file-5>
        <file-6>apps/web/vite.config.*</file-6>
        <file-7>apps/web/vitest.config.*</file-7>
        <file-8>apps/web/src/main.*</file-8>
        <file-9>apps/web/src/vite-env.d.ts</file-9>
        <file-10>apps/web/src/app/*</file-10>
        <file-11>apps/web/src/features/jobs/*</file-11>
        <file-12>apps/web/src/features/artifacts/*</file-12>
        <file-13>apps/web/src/lib/api/*</file-13>
        <file-14>apps/web/tests/*</file-14>
      </write-scope>
      <write-scope-notes>
        <note-1>Only materialize the app-local shell, entry files, config, env contract, packet-local API client boundary, and test harness needed to make `pnpm --dir apps/web test` runnable.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not start jobs list, job details, polling or WebSocket reconciliation, artifact resolve, or admin action behavior in this unblock packet.</note-2>
        <note-3>Do not add root workspace files unless a concrete blocker proves the app-local manifest cannot run standalone.</note-3>
        <note-4>If `packages/sdk-ts` is absent, keep a thin local client inside `apps/web/src/lib/api` instead of broadening Phase-5 into a separate SDK packet.</note-4>
      </write-scope-notes>
      <contract-excerpt><![CDATA[
DevelopmentPlan / M-WEB-UI:
- Purpose: expose the local browser UI for submission, monitoring, artifact download, and late-wave admin operations.
- Scope: jobs list, job details, uploads, URL submission, artifact resolution, polling and WS reconciliation, and late-wave admin actions.
- Links: M-WEB-UI, V-M-WEB-UI, DF-001, DF-003, DF-006, DF-007.
- Error: ui_state_drift.

Phase-5 step-0:
- Create the minimal `apps/web` scaffold and app-local test harness required before Web UI feature work begins.
- Cover the original scaffold responsibilities: route shell, layout shell, env contract, and API client wiring.
- Keep this unblock step inside the Web UI app shell only so `M-WEB-UI-wave-5` can resume without widening into API or adapter packets.
      ]]></contract-excerpt>
      <graph-entry-excerpt><![CDATA[
KnowledgeGraph / M-WEB-UI:
- Path: apps/web
- Depends: M-CONTRACTS, M-API-HTTP, M-API-EVENTS
- Verification ref: V-M-WEB-UI
- Purpose: provide local file/url submission, monitoring, artifact download, and late-wave admin operations.
- Public annotations remain planned and are fulfilled by the follow-on implementation packet, not by this scaffold packet.
      ]]></graph-entry-excerpt>
      <dependency-contract-summaries>
        <dependency-1 module="M-CONTRACTS">The app shell must preserve the canonical contract boundary so later form, job, and artifact flows still consume the frozen API and event envelopes rather than inventing local truth.</dependency-1>
        <dependency-2 module="M-API-HTTP">This unblock packet prepares an API-consuming UI surface only; it must not move submission, action, or artifact logic into the client.</dependency-2>
        <dependency-3 module="M-API-EVENTS">Do not introduce WebSocket ownership or reconciliation behavior yet; that remains explicit follow-on work in `M-WEB-UI-wave-5`.</dependency-3>
      </dependency-contract-summaries>
      <verification-excerpt><![CDATA[
VerificationPlan / V-M-WEB-UI / execution prerequisite:
- Module check: pnpm --dir apps/web test
- Execution prerequisite: if `apps/web` is absent, materialize the scoped app shell and test harness before UI feature work starts.
- The shell should leave behind `VITE_API_BASE_URL`, `VITE_WS_URL`, route or layout bootstrap, and a mockable local API client boundary.
- Marker reminder: [WebUi][reconcileState][BLOCK_RECONCILE_POLLING_AND_WS_STATE] remains a requirement for the follow-on implementation packet and must not be faked here.
      ]]></verification-excerpt>
      <step-local-verification>
        <command-1>pnpm --dir apps/web test</command-1>
        <evidence-1>`apps/web` exists with an app-local manifest, env template, route or layout shell, packet-local API boundary, and test harness so the follow-on packet can stay inside `src/app`, features, lib/api, and tests.</evidence-1>
        <evidence-2>No client-side business logic, event ownership, or source-of-truth drift is introduced while removing the scaffold blocker.</evidence-2>
      </step-local-verification>
      <expected-graph-delta-fields>
        <field-1>imports: keep future dependencies bounded to M-CONTRACTS, M-API-HTTP, and M-API-EVENTS; do not add direct storage or queue edges.</field-1>
        <field-2>exports: materialize only the app shell entry surface needed for the follow-on jobs and details pages.</field-2>
        <field-3>annotations: preserve the planned `export-jobsPage` and `export-jobDetailsPage` expectations without claiming feature-complete behavior in this packet.</field-3>
        <field-4>CrossLinks: preserve the planned UI-to-API and UI-to-event relationships; do not broaden ownership links.</field-4>
      </expected-graph-delta-fields>
      <expected-verification-delta-fields>
        <field-1>test-files: add only the minimal app-shell tests under `apps/web/tests` required to make the module check runnable.</field-1>
        <field-2>module-checks: make `pnpm --dir apps/web test` pass and preserve it unchanged for the follow-on packet.</field-2>
        <field-3>required-log-markers: preserve `[WebUi][reconcileState][BLOCK_RECONCILE_POLLING_AND_WS_STATE]` as a later requirement; do not simulate it in scaffold code.</field-3>
        <field-4>follow-up-checks: jobs, artifacts, browser smoke, and polling or WebSocket reconciliation remain explicit work for `M-WEB-UI-wave-5`.</field-4>
        <field-5>prep-artifacts: leave `apps/web/.env.example` plus mockable `src/lib/api` boundaries so the follow-on packet does not reopen shell-level plumbing.</field-5>
      </expected-verification-delta-fields>
      <notes>
        <note-1>This packet exists only to remove the missing-app-shell blocker that prevented `M-WEB-UI-wave-5` from starting safely.</note-1>
        <note-2>Resume `M-WEB-UI-wave-5` immediately after this unblock packet passes.</note-2>
      </notes>
    </ExecutionPacket>

    <ExecutionPacket packet-id="M-WEB-UI-wave-5" module="M-WEB-UI" phase="Phase-5" step="1" verification-ref="V-M-WEB-UI">
      <module-id>M-WEB-UI</module-id>
      <module-name>WebUi</module-name>
      <purpose>Implement the local browser UI for submission, monitoring, artifact download, and admin details while keeping polling authoritative and using WebSocket only as the low-latency update path.</purpose>
      <write-scope>
        <file-1>apps/web/src/app/*</file-1>
        <file-2>apps/web/src/features/jobs/*</file-2>
        <file-3>apps/web/src/features/artifacts/*</file-3>
        <file-4>apps/web/src/lib/api/*</file-4>
        <file-5>apps/web/tests/*</file-5>
      </write-scope>
      <write-scope-notes>
        <note-0>Execute `M-WEB-UI-app-shell-wave-5` first whenever `apps/web` or its app-local test harness is still missing.</note-0>
        <note-1>Keep this packet inside the Web UI app and its local tests only.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not move API business logic or event ownership into the UI; the UI consumes API plus event surfaces only.</note-2>
        <note-3>If `packages/sdk-ts` is absent, keep a thin packet-local API client under `apps/web/src/lib/api` instead of broadening Phase-5 into a separate SDK packet.</note-3>
      </write-scope-notes>
      <contract-excerpt><![CDATA[
DevelopmentPlan / M-WEB-UI:
- Purpose: expose the local browser UI for submission, monitoring, artifact download, and late-wave admin operations.
- Scope: jobs list, job details, uploads, URL submission, artifact resolution, polling and WS reconciliation, and late-wave admin actions.
- Links: M-WEB-UI, V-M-WEB-UI, DF-001, DF-003, DF-006, DF-007.
- Error: ui_state_drift.

Wave-6 + ImplementationOrder / Phase-5 step-1:
- Create jobs list and job details pages.
- Add create-job form for per-file upload, combined multi-media upload, and YouTube URL submission.
- Add polling and WebSocket integration using polling as fallback and WebSocket for fast updates.
- Add report, deep research, cancel, retry, delivery-strategy controls, and late-wave admin operations.
      ]]></contract-excerpt>
      <graph-entry-excerpt><![CDATA[
KnowledgeGraph / M-WEB-UI:
- Path: apps/web
- Depends: M-CONTRACTS, M-API-HTTP, M-API-EVENTS
- Verification ref: V-M-WEB-UI
- Purpose: provide local file/url submission, monitoring, artifact download, and late-wave admin operations.
- Public annotations already expected in the graph:
  - export-jobsPage
  - export-jobDetailsPage

Existing CrossLinks:
- M-WEB-UI -> M-API-HTTP relation="consumes"
- M-WEB-UI -> M-API-EVENTS relation="subscribes-to"
      ]]></graph-entry-excerpt>
      <dependency-contract-summaries>
        <dependency-1 module="M-CONTRACTS">Form submissions, job reads, artifact resolution, error handling, and delivery-strategy controls must stay aligned with the canonical API and event envelopes.</dependency-1>
        <dependency-2 module="M-API-HTTP">UI consumes the polling truth path, create-job routes, child-job actions, retry, cancel, and artifact resolution through the API only.</dependency-2>
        <dependency-3 module="M-API-EVENTS">WebSocket updates are a low-latency event stream and must always reconcile back to REST on reconnect or version gap.</dependency-3>
      </dependency-contract-summaries>
      <verification-excerpt><![CDATA[
VerificationPlan / V-M-WEB-UI / Gate-Phase-5:
- Module check: pnpm --dir apps/web test
- Success scenario: UI creates jobs, reconciles polling and WebSocket state, and resolves artifacts via API.
- Failure scenario: expired links and unsupported admin operations fail through API responses rather than client-side guesswork.
- Required marker: [WebUi][reconcileState][BLOCK_RECONCILE_POLLING_AND_WS_STATE]
- Required assertion: UI must re-fetch from REST on WebSocket reconnect or version gap.
- Wave follow-up: run browser smoke tests once the app exists.
- Phase follow-up: cover late-wave admin actions and delete constraints.
      ]]></verification-excerpt>
      <step-local-verification>
        <command-1>pnpm --dir apps/web test</command-1>
        <command-2>Browser-local smoke coverage for upload, combined upload, URL create, job details, artifact resolve, and polling or WebSocket reconciliation.</command-2>
        <evidence-1>UI preserves polling as the authoritative read path while using WebSocket only for latency reduction.</evidence-1>
        <evidence-2>Admin actions and expired-link refresh flows surface API truth instead of client-side inferred state.</evidence-2>
      </step-local-verification>
      <expected-graph-delta-fields>
        <field-1>imports: confirm stable dependencies on M-CONTRACTS, M-API-HTTP, and M-API-EVENTS.</field-1>
        <field-2>exports: confirm stable jobs-page and job-details-page entrypoints.</field-2>
        <field-3>annotations: refine only public UI entrypoints and event-reconciliation notes that remain stable.</field-3>
        <field-4>CrossLinks: preserve UI consumption of API plus event subscription links; do not add direct storage or queue edges.</field-4>
      </expected-graph-delta-fields>
      <expected-verification-delta-fields>
        <field-1>test-files: add concrete Web UI tests under `apps/web/tests`.</field-1>
        <field-2>module-checks: preserve the app-local `pnpm --dir apps/web test` command.</field-2>
        <field-3>required-log-markers: preserve `[WebUi][reconcileState][BLOCK_RECONCILE_POLLING_AND_WS_STATE]`.</field-3>
        <field-4>follow-up-checks: browser smoke and late-wave admin coverage remain explicit follow-ups after the core UI packet lands.</field-4>
      </expected-verification-delta-fields>
      <notes>
        <note-1>Do not let the UI become a hidden source of truth for job state.</note-1>
        <note-2>Keep packet scope on the browser app; SDK regeneration or API refactoring is out of scope unless blocking.</note-2>
      </notes>
    </ExecutionPacket>

    <ExecutionPacket packet-id="M-TELEGRAM-ADAPTER-wave-5" module="M-TELEGRAM-ADAPTER" phase="Phase-5" step="2" verification-ref="V-M-TELEGRAM-ADAPTER">
      <module-id>M-TELEGRAM-ADAPTER</module-id>
      <module-name>TelegramAdapter</module-name>
      <purpose>Replace bot-side orchestration with API calls while preserving the current Telegram UX, polling-default delivery, media-group combined submission, and artifact callback flows.</purpose>
      <write-scope>
        <file-1>apps/telegram-bot/pyproject.toml</file-1>
        <file-2>apps/telegram-bot/.env.example</file-2>
        <file-3>apps/telegram-bot/src/**/*.py</file-3>
        <file-4>apps/telegram-bot/tests/*.py</file-4>
        <file-5>tests/test_bot.py</file-5>
        <file-6>tests/test_media_groups.py</file-6>
        <file-7>tests/test_main.py</file-7>
        <file-8>src/telegram_transcriber_bot/bot.py</file-8>
      </write-scope>
      <write-scope-notes>
        <note-1>Touch the current `bot.py` only to remove execution coupling and preserve user-visible bot flows through the adapter boundary.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not reintroduce local execution logic into the adapter; all business behavior remains API-owned.</note-2>
        <note-3>If `apps/telegram-bot` is absent, create the minimal adapter root, env contract, and package metadata inside this packet instead of introducing a separate shell packet.</note-3>
        <note-4>If `packages/sdk-py` is absent, keep a thin packet-local API client under the adapter boundary instead of broadening Phase-5 into a separate SDK packet.</note-4>
      </write-scope-notes>
      <contract-excerpt><![CDATA[
DevelopmentPlan / M-TELEGRAM-ADAPTER:
- Purpose: preserve Telegram UX while delegating all business logic to the API.
- Scope: Telegram update parsing, temporary media download, API submission, polling wait flow, callback mapping, and artifact sending.
- Links: M-TELEGRAM-ADAPTER, V-M-TELEGRAM-ADAPTER, DF-001, DF-004, DF-005, DF-007.
- Error: telegram_upload_failed.

Wave-7 + ImplementationOrder / Phase-5 step-2:
- Add typed Python API client support for create upload job, combined upload, URL job, get/list job, child-job create, cancel, retry, and artifact resolution.
- Map Telegram media groups to the combined endpoint and allow explicit buffered combined submission for sequential media.
- Preserve plain transcript delivery, segmented transcript button, report button, and deep research button.
- Remove execution coupling so the bot no longer imports execution core directly.
      ]]></contract-excerpt>
      <graph-entry-excerpt><![CDATA[
KnowledgeGraph / M-TELEGRAM-ADAPTER:
- Path: apps/telegram-bot
- Depends: M-CONTRACTS, M-API-HTTP
- Verification ref: V-M-TELEGRAM-ADAPTER
- Purpose: act as a thin Telegram transport client over the HTTP API while preserving current user-visible bot flows.
- Public annotations already expected in the graph:
  - export-handleIncomingMedia
  - export-handleCallbacks
  - export-submitCombinedMedia

Existing CrossLinks:
- M-TELEGRAM-ADAPTER -> M-API-HTTP relation="consumes"
      ]]></graph-entry-excerpt>
      <dependency-contract-summaries>
        <dependency-1 module="M-CONTRACTS">Telegram request shaping, artifact delivery, callback actions, and error handling must stay aligned with the canonical API contract and artifact metadata shapes.</dependency-1>
        <dependency-2 module="M-API-HTTP">The adapter submits uploads, combined-media jobs, URL jobs, child-job actions, retry, cancel, and artifact resolution through the API only.</dependency-2>
      </dependency-contract-summaries>
      <verification-excerpt><![CDATA[
VerificationPlan / V-M-TELEGRAM-ADAPTER / Gate-Phase-5:
- Module check: .venv/bin/python -m pytest --no-cov tests/test_bot.py tests/test_media_groups.py tests/test_main.py
- App-local client check: PYTHONPATH=apps/telegram-bot/src .venv/bin/python -m pytest --no-cov apps/telegram-bot/tests/test_api_client.py
- Execution prerequisite: if `apps/telegram-bot` is absent, materialize adapter root files and env contract inside the packet.
- Success scenario: Telegram adapter uploads media to the API and returns resulting artifacts while preserving current UX.
- Failure scenario: Telegram callback flows do not bypass API lineage and child-job rules.
- Required marker: [TelegramAdapter][handleMedia][BLOCK_SUBMIT_AND_WAIT_FOR_JOB]
- Required assertions:
  - default Telegram delivery strategy remains polling;
  - media groups map to the combined transcription flow instead of the per-file upload flow.
- Wave follow-up: replay current plain-transcript and segmented/report button UX through the new adapter.
- Phase follow-up: validate Telegram runtime under the compose stack before deleting the old entrypoint.
      ]]></verification-excerpt>
      <step-local-verification>
        <command-1>.venv/bin/python -m pytest --no-cov tests/test_bot.py tests/test_media_groups.py tests/test_main.py</command-1>
        <command-2>PYTHONPATH=apps/telegram-bot/src .venv/bin/python -m pytest --no-cov apps/telegram-bot/tests/test_api_client.py</command-2>
        <command-3>Adapter-local replay coverage for plain transcript, segmented transcript, report, deep-research, retry, and combined-media callback flows.</command-3>
        <evidence-1>Bot behavior preserves the current user-visible flow while delegating execution and lineage ownership to the API.</evidence-1>
        <evidence-2>Media groups and buffered sequential media route to the combined endpoint instead of spawning unrelated per-file jobs.</evidence-2>
        <evidence-3>The adapter packet leaves behind any missing app-root metadata and env contract files without broadening into shared-SDK work.</evidence-3>
      </step-local-verification>
      <expected-graph-delta-fields>
        <field-1>imports: confirm stable dependency on M-CONTRACTS and M-API-HTTP only.</field-1>
        <field-2>exports: confirm incoming-media, callback, and combined-submission adapter entrypoints.</field-2>
        <field-3>annotations: refine only stable Telegram adapter entrypoints that remain public module surface.</field-3>
        <field-4>CrossLinks: preserve the single adapter-to-API consumption boundary; do not add worker or storage ownership links.</field-4>
      </expected-graph-delta-fields>
      <expected-verification-delta-fields>
        <field-1>test-files: preserve current Telegram regression tests and add adapter-local tests under `apps/telegram-bot/tests` if needed.</field-1>
        <field-2>module-checks: keep the narrow Telegram pytest command.</field-2>
        <field-3>required-log-markers: preserve `[TelegramAdapter][handleMedia][BLOCK_SUBMIT_AND_WAIT_FOR_JOB]`.</field-3>
        <field-4>follow-up-checks: compose-stack runtime verification remains phase follow-up after adapter extraction.</field-4>
        <field-5>prep-artifacts: if needed, materialize `apps/telegram-bot/pyproject.toml` and `.env.example` inside packet scope.</field-5>
      </expected-verification-delta-fields>
      <notes>
        <note-1>Telegram remains a transport adapter, not a second orchestration plane.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not regress plain transcript immediacy while extracting the adapter.</note-2>
        <note-3>If `packages/sdk-py` is absent, keep a thin adapter-local API client inside the packet scope instead of broadening Phase-5 into a separate SDK packet.</note-3>
      </notes>
    </ExecutionPacket>

    <ExecutionPacket packet-id="M-MCP-ADAPTER-app-shell-wave-5" module="M-MCP-ADAPTER" phase="Phase-5" step="0b" verification-ref="V-M-MCP-ADAPTER">
      <module-id>M-MCP-ADAPTER</module-id>
      <module-name>McpAdapter</module-name>
      <purpose>Create the minimal `apps/mcp-server` application shell and app-local test harness required so the MCP adapter implementation packet can execute inside its declared source and test scope without widening into API, SDK, or Web UI work.</purpose>
      <write-scope>
        <file-1>apps/mcp-server/package.json</file-1>
        <file-2>apps/mcp-server/pnpm-lock.yaml</file-2>
        <file-3>apps/mcp-server/.env.example</file-3>
        <file-4>apps/mcp-server/tsconfig*.json</file-4>
        <file-5>apps/mcp-server/vitest.config.*</file-5>
        <file-6>apps/mcp-server/src/index.ts</file-6>
        <file-7>apps/mcp-server/src/client/*</file-7>
        <file-8>apps/mcp-server/src/tools/*</file-8>
        <file-9>apps/mcp-server/tests/*</file-9>
      </write-scope>
      <write-scope-notes>
        <note-1>Only materialize the app-local shell, config, env contract, entrypoint, packet-local API client boundary, and test harness needed to make `pnpm --dir apps/mcp-server test` runnable.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not implement tool mapping, artifact visibility, or API business behavior in this unblock packet.</note-2>
        <note-3>Do not broaden into `packages/sdk-ts`; if the SDK package is still absent, the follow-on packet may keep a thin local client inside `apps/mcp-server/src`.</note-3>
      </write-scope-notes>
      <contract-excerpt><![CDATA[
DevelopmentPlan / M-MCP-ADAPTER:
- Purpose: expose the platform as an MCP surface over the same typed HTTP API client.
- Scope: MCP tool definitions, API request mapping, result shaping, and tool-level read/write parity with the HTTP API.
- Links: M-MCP-ADAPTER, V-M-MCP-ADAPTER, DF-001, DF-004, DF-005, DF-007.
- Error: mcp_contract_violation.

Phase-5 step-0b:
- Create the minimal `apps/mcp-server` scaffold and app-local test harness required before MCP tool-mapping work begins.
- Cover the original scaffold responsibilities: server bootstrap, tool-registry shell, env contract, and API client wiring.
- Keep this unblock step inside the MCP adapter app shell only so `M-MCP-ADAPTER-wave-5` can resume without widening into SDK or API packets.
      ]]></contract-excerpt>
      <graph-entry-excerpt><![CDATA[
KnowledgeGraph / M-MCP-ADAPTER:
- Path: apps/mcp-server
- Depends: M-CONTRACTS, M-API-HTTP
- Verification ref: V-M-MCP-ADAPTER
- Purpose: expose the same platform capabilities to MCP consumers through a thin adapter over the HTTP API.
- Public annotations remain planned and are fulfilled by the follow-on implementation packet, not by this scaffold packet.
      ]]></graph-entry-excerpt>
      <dependency-contract-summaries>
        <dependency-1 module="M-CONTRACTS">The app shell must preserve canonical request and response envelope boundaries so later MCP tools remain contract-shaped and do not invent parallel tool semantics.</dependency-1>
        <dependency-2 module="M-API-HTTP">This unblock packet prepares an API-consuming adapter surface only; it must not absorb persistence, queue, worker, or artifact-ownership logic.</dependency-2>
      </dependency-contract-summaries>
      <verification-excerpt><![CDATA[
VerificationPlan / V-M-MCP-ADAPTER / execution prerequisite:
- Module check: pnpm --dir apps/mcp-server test
- Execution prerequisite: if `apps/mcp-server` is absent, materialize the scoped MCP app shell and test harness before tool-mapping work starts.
- The shell should leave behind `API_BASE_URL`, server or tool-registry bootstrap, and a mockable local API client boundary.
- Marker reminder: [McpAdapter][mapToolToApi][BLOCK_MAP_MCP_TOOL_TO_API_CALL] remains a requirement for the follow-on implementation packet and must not be faked here.
      ]]></verification-excerpt>
      <step-local-verification>
        <command-1>pnpm --dir apps/mcp-server test</command-1>
        <evidence-1>`apps/mcp-server` exists with an app-local manifest, env template, entrypoint, local API boundary, and test harness so the follow-on packet can stay inside `src` and `tests`.</evidence-1>
        <evidence-2>No direct DB, queue, MinIO, or business-logic ownership is introduced while removing the missing-app-shell blocker.</evidence-2>
      </step-local-verification>
      <expected-graph-delta-fields>
        <field-1>imports: keep future dependencies bounded to M-CONTRACTS and M-API-HTTP only.</field-1>
        <field-2>exports: materialize only the entry surface needed for the follow-on MCP tools.</field-2>
        <field-3>annotations: preserve the planned MCP tool export expectations without claiming feature-complete behavior in this packet.</field-3>
        <field-4>CrossLinks: preserve the planned adapter-to-API relationship and avoid any direct infra links.</field-4>
      </expected-graph-delta-fields>
      <expected-verification-delta-fields>
        <field-1>test-files: add only the minimal MCP app-shell tests under `apps/mcp-server/tests` required to make the module check runnable.</field-1>
        <field-2>module-checks: make `pnpm --dir apps/mcp-server test` pass and preserve it unchanged for the follow-on packet.</field-2>
        <field-3>required-log-markers: preserve `[McpAdapter][mapToolToApi][BLOCK_MAP_MCP_TOOL_TO_API_CALL]` as a later requirement; do not simulate it in scaffold code.</field-3>
        <field-4>follow-up-checks: tool mapping, artifact visibility, and live-API integration remain explicit work for `M-MCP-ADAPTER-wave-5`.</field-4>
        <field-5>prep-artifacts: leave `apps/mcp-server/.env.example` plus mockable `src/client` boundaries so the follow-on packet does not reopen shell-level plumbing.</field-5>
      </expected-verification-delta-fields>
      <notes>
        <note-1>This packet exists only to remove the missing-app-shell blocker that prevented `M-MCP-ADAPTER-wave-5` from starting safely.</note-1>
        <note-2>Resume `M-MCP-ADAPTER-wave-5` immediately after this unblock packet passes.</note-2>
      </notes>
    </ExecutionPacket>

    <ExecutionPacket packet-id="M-MCP-ADAPTER-wave-5" module="M-MCP-ADAPTER" phase="Phase-5" step="3" verification-ref="V-M-MCP-ADAPTER">
      <module-id>M-MCP-ADAPTER</module-id>
      <module-name>McpAdapter</module-name>
      <purpose>Expose the platform through a thin MCP adapter that maps tool calls to the existing HTTP API without introducing direct storage, queue, or business-logic access.</purpose>
      <write-scope>
        <file-1>apps/mcp-server/src/index.ts</file-1>
        <file-2>apps/mcp-server/src/tools/*</file-2>
        <file-3>apps/mcp-server/tests/*</file-3>
      </write-scope>
      <write-scope-notes>
        <note-0>Execute `M-MCP-ADAPTER-app-shell-wave-5` first whenever `apps/mcp-server` or its app-local test harness is still missing.</note-0>
        <note-1>Keep this packet in the MCP adapter code and its local tests only.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not add direct DB, Redis, MinIO, or worker-runtime access in this packet.</note-2>
        <note-3>If `packages/sdk-ts` is absent, keep a thin local client inside `apps/mcp-server/src` instead of broadening Phase-5 into a separate SDK packet.</note-3>
        <note-4>Assume env contract, server bootstrap, and local client boundary were materialized by `M-MCP-ADAPTER-app-shell-wave-5` before tool mapping begins.</note-4>
      </write-scope-notes>
      <contract-excerpt><![CDATA[
DevelopmentPlan / M-MCP-ADAPTER:
- Purpose: expose the platform as an MCP surface over the same typed HTTP API client.
- Scope: MCP tool definitions, API request mapping, result shaping, and tool-level read/write parity with the HTTP API.
- Links: M-MCP-ADAPTER, V-M-MCP-ADAPTER, DF-001, DF-004, DF-005, DF-007.
- Error: mcp_contract_violation.

Wave-8 + ImplementationOrder / Phase-5 step-3:
- Scaffold MCP server.
- Add core tools for create transcription job, get job, list jobs, create report job, create deep-research job, cancel, and retry.
- Add artifact visibility through artifact metadata and download endpoints.
      ]]></contract-excerpt>
      <graph-entry-excerpt><![CDATA[
KnowledgeGraph / M-MCP-ADAPTER:
- Path: apps/mcp-server
- Depends: M-CONTRACTS, M-API-HTTP
- Verification ref: V-M-MCP-ADAPTER
- Purpose: expose the same platform capabilities to MCP consumers through a thin adapter over the HTTP API.
- Public annotations already expected in the graph:
  - export-createTranscriptionJob
  - export-inspectJob

Existing CrossLinks:
- M-MCP-ADAPTER -> M-API-HTTP relation="consumes"
      ]]></graph-entry-excerpt>
      <dependency-contract-summaries>
        <dependency-1 module="M-CONTRACTS">Tool request and response shaping, artifact metadata reads, and error envelopes must stay aligned with the canonical contract package.</dependency-1>
        <dependency-2 module="M-API-HTTP">Every MCP tool maps to API operations instead of duplicating persistence, queue, or worker logic locally.</dependency-2>
      </dependency-contract-summaries>
      <verification-excerpt><![CDATA[
VerificationPlan / V-M-MCP-ADAPTER / Gate-Phase-5:
- Module check: pnpm --dir apps/mcp-server test
- Success scenario: MCP tools map cleanly onto API operations without hidden business logic.
- Failure scenario: adapter-level validation and error propagation stay contract-shaped and do not fall back to direct storage or queue access.
- Required marker: [McpAdapter][mapToolToApi][BLOCK_MAP_MCP_TOOL_TO_API_CALL]
- Required assertion: MCP must not require direct DB, queue, or MinIO access.
- Wave follow-up: run tool-level integration against a live API container.
- Phase follow-up: check parity with the Web UI and Telegram capability surface.
      ]]></verification-excerpt>
      <step-local-verification>
        <command-1>pnpm --dir apps/mcp-server test</command-1>
        <command-2>Tool-mapping checks covering create job, inspect job, artifact visibility, cancel, retry, report, and deep-research actions through the API surface.</command-2>
        <evidence-1>MCP remains a thin adapter over the API and exposes no hidden direct infrastructure access.</evidence-1>
        <evidence-2>Tool responses stay contract-shaped for both success and deterministic failure paths.</evidence-2>
      </step-local-verification>
      <expected-graph-delta-fields>
        <field-1>imports: confirm stable dependencies on M-CONTRACTS and M-API-HTTP only.</field-1>
        <field-2>exports: confirm stable create-job and inspect-job tool entrypoints.</field-2>
        <field-3>annotations: refine only stable MCP adapter tool exports.</field-3>
        <field-4>CrossLinks: preserve the adapter-to-API consumption boundary and avoid any direct infra links.</field-4>
      </expected-graph-delta-fields>
      <expected-verification-delta-fields>
        <field-1>test-files: add concrete adapter tests under `apps/mcp-server/tests`.</field-1>
        <field-2>module-checks: preserve the app-local `pnpm --dir apps/mcp-server test` command.</field-2>
        <field-3>required-log-markers: preserve `[McpAdapter][mapToolToApi][BLOCK_MAP_MCP_TOOL_TO_API_CALL]`.</field-3>
        <field-4>follow-up-checks: live-API integration and cross-surface parity remain later checks outside the initial adapter packet.</field-4>
      </expected-verification-delta-fields>
      <notes>
        <note-1>MCP is a strict adapter surface, not a parallel control plane.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not let tool handlers absorb business rules that already belong to the API job layer.</note-2>
      </notes>
    </ExecutionPacket>

    <ExecutionPacket packet-id="M-INFRA-COMPOSE-wave-6" module="M-INFRA-COMPOSE" phase="Phase-6" step="1" verification-ref="V-M-INFRA-COMPOSE">
      <module-id>M-INFRA-COMPOSE</module-id>
      <module-name>InfraCompose</module-name>
      <purpose>Harden the compose stack for the post-implementation phase by proving startup order, healthchecks, persistent volumes, and stack-local smoke execution before final cutover.</purpose>
      <packet-state>completed</packet-state>
      <completion-evidence>docker compose config, compose-smoke --check-config, and compose-smoke --live-smoke passed with API, workers, Web UI, Telegram adapter, MCP adapter, Postgres, Redis, MinIO, and MinIO init converged.</completion-evidence>
      <write-scope>
        <file-1>infra/docker-compose.yml</file-1>
        <file-2>infra/env/*.env.example</file-2>
        <file-3>infra/init/*</file-3>
        <file-4>infra/scripts/compose-smoke.sh</file-4>
      </write-scope>
      <write-scope-notes>
        <note-1>Keep this packet inside compose topology, env contracts, init scripts, and smoke verification assets.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not move application business logic into compose files; this packet hardens runtime wiring only.</note-2>
      </write-scope-notes>
      <contract-excerpt><![CDATA[
DevelopmentPlan / M-INFRA-COMPOSE:
- Purpose: own local Docker Compose topology, service dependencies, and environment contracts.
- Scope: compose topology, healthchecks, startup ordering, volumes, service env contracts, and smoke-run expectations.
- Links: M-INFRA-COMPOSE, V-M-INFRA-COMPOSE, DF-001, DF-003, DF-006, DF-007.
- Error: compose_boot_failed.

Wave-9 + ImplementationOrder / Phase-6 step-1:
- Add persistent volumes and init scripts.
- Add healthchecks.
- Harden startup order and smoke scripts.
- Finish compose-local readiness before the old single-process runtime path can be removed.
      ]]></contract-excerpt>
      <graph-entry-excerpt><![CDATA[
KnowledgeGraph / M-INFRA-COMPOSE:
- Path: infra/docker-compose.yml
- Depends: M-API-HTTP, M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION, M-WORKER-REPORT, M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH, M-WEB-UI, M-TELEGRAM-ADAPTER, M-MCP-ADAPTER
- Verification ref: V-M-INFRA-COMPOSE
- Purpose: define and bootstrap the local runtime topology for API, workers, adapters, and storage dependencies.
- Public annotations already expected in the graph:
  - export-composeStack

Existing CrossLinks:
- M-INFRA-COMPOSE -> M-API-HTTP relation="runs"
- M-INFRA-COMPOSE -> M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION relation="runs"
- M-INFRA-COMPOSE -> M-WORKER-REPORT relation="runs"
- M-INFRA-COMPOSE -> M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH relation="runs"
      ]]></graph-entry-excerpt>
      <dependency-contract-summaries>
        <dependency-1 module="all-runtime-modules">Compose hardening is only valid after API, workers, UI, Telegram, and MCP modules expose stable runtime entrypoints.</dependency-1>
        <dependency-2 module="M-CONTRACTS-runtime-assumptions">Healthchecks, env wiring, and smoke scripts must respect the already-frozen control-plane and worker boundaries rather than adding side-channel integrations.</dependency-2>
      </dependency-contract-summaries>
      <verification-excerpt><![CDATA[
VerificationPlan / V-M-INFRA-COMPOSE / Gate-Phase-6:
- Module checks:
  - docker compose -f infra/docker-compose.yml config
  - bash infra/scripts/compose-smoke.sh --check-config
- Success scenario: compose topology defines the required services, env-file contracts, healthchecks, volumes, and startup ordering before runtime modules are implemented.
- Success scenario: once runtime modules exist, compose smoke verification proves healthcheck convergence, startup order, and persistent volume wiring before cutover.
- Failure scenario: missing services, env contracts, or invalid compose wiring fail fast through config validation and smoke-script checks.
- Required marker: [InfraCompose][verifyLocalStack][BLOCK_VERIFY_LOCAL_STACK_HEALTH]
- Required assertions:
  - Phase-1 validates topology shape only; full stack boot remains a later phase gate after service modules exist;
  - Phase-6 hardening must prove clean stack startup and smoke-script success before the old single-process runtime path is removed.
- Wave follow-up: exercise healthchecks and startup ordering under clean local state once API and worker entrypoints exist.
- Phase follow-up: run full smoke matrix before deleting the old single-process runtime path.
      ]]></verification-excerpt>
      <step-local-verification>
        <command-1>docker compose -f infra/docker-compose.yml config</command-1>
        <command-2>bash infra/scripts/compose-smoke.sh --check-config</command-2>
        <command-3>bash infra/scripts/compose-smoke.sh --live-smoke</command-3>
        <command-4>WEB_HOST_PORT=3300 docker compose -f infra/docker-compose.yml up -d web</command-4>
        <evidence-1>Stack startup order and healthchecks converge without manual ordering hacks.</evidence-1>
        <evidence-2>Persistent volume and init-script wiring are proven before cutover rather than assumed from config shape alone.</evidence-2>
        <evidence-3>Browser smoke can target a non-default host port when local port 3000 is occupied by an unrelated process.</evidence-3>
      </step-local-verification>
      <expected-graph-delta-fields>
        <field-1>imports: runtime module dependency set should remain stable unless compose gains or drops a real service boundary.</field-1>
        <field-2>exports: confirm `export-composeStack` remains the stable compose-owned public interface.</field-2>
        <field-3>annotations: refine only healthcheck or smoke-run annotations that become stable and public.</field-3>
        <field-4>CrossLinks: preserve runtime `runs` edges and avoid adding business-logic ownership edges.</field-4>
      </expected-graph-delta-fields>
      <expected-verification-delta-fields>
        <field-1>test-files: keep compose, env-example, init-script, and smoke-script coverage inside `infra/`.</field-1>
        <field-2>module-checks: preserve config validation plus compose smoke commands as authoritative checks.</field-2>
        <field-3>required-log-markers: preserve `[InfraCompose][verifyLocalStack][BLOCK_VERIFY_LOCAL_STACK_HEALTH]`.</field-3>
        <field-4>follow-up-checks: compose health convergence is closed; full functional smoke matrix remains the final phase gate before cutover.</field-4>
      </expected-verification-delta-fields>
      <notes>
        <note-1>This packet is runtime hardening, not new architecture.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not claim cutover readiness until compose smoke proves the post-implementation stack, not only YAML validity.</note-2>
      </notes>
    </ExecutionPacket>

    <ExecutionPacket packet-id="M-API-HTTP-wave-6" module="M-API-HTTP" phase="Phase-6" step="2" verification-ref="V-M-API-HTTP">
      <module-id>M-API-HTTP</module-id>
      <module-name>ApiHttp</module-name>
      <purpose>Close the cutover wave by proving full-stack API parity against the frozen acceptance matrix and keeping any final HTTP-layer changes limited to route-level gaps surfaced by evidence.</purpose>
      <packet-state>next-open</packet-state>
      <entry-condition>Start only after M-INFRA-COMPOSE-wave-6 is completed and compose live-smoke health convergence is proven.</entry-condition>
      <write-scope>
        <file-1>apps/api/internal/api/*_test.go</file-1>
        <file-2>apps/api/internal/api/testdata/*</file-2>
        <file-3>apps/api/cmd/api/main.go</file-3>
      </write-scope>
      <write-scope-notes>
        <note-1>Default to route-level tests, fixtures, and narrow HTTP-boundary adjustments only.</note-1>
        <note-2>Do not reopen jobs, storage, queue, or event architecture in this packet unless a parity failure proves the HTTP boundary is the first divergent block.</note-2>
      </write-scope-notes>
      <contract-excerpt><![CDATA[
DevelopmentPlan / M-API-HTTP:
- Purpose: expose public and internal HTTP routes that bind incoming requests to API job orchestration logic.
- Scope: multipart upload handling, JSON request validation, route binding, error envelopes, and WebSocket session entry.
- Links: M-API-HTTP, V-M-API-HTTP, DF-001, DF-002, DF-003, DF-004, DF-005, DF-006, DF-007.
- Errors: validation_failed, dependency_unavailable.

ImplementationOrder / Phase-6 step-2 + CutoverParity:
- Verify full-stack parity against the frozen acceptance matrix before deleting the old runtime path.
- Public and internal worker routes remain explicit.
- Polling remains authoritative even when WebSocket and webhook delivery succeed.
- Late-wave route fixes are allowed only when parity evidence proves the HTTP boundary is the divergent block.
      ]]></contract-excerpt>
      <graph-entry-excerpt><![CDATA[
KnowledgeGraph / M-API-HTTP:
- Path: apps/api/internal/api
- Depends: M-CONTRACTS, M-API-JOBS, M-API-STORAGE, M-API-QUEUE, M-API-EVENTS
- Verification ref: V-M-API-HTTP
- Purpose: expose create, list, get, cancel, retry, artifact, event, and internal worker endpoints for the control plane.
- Public annotations already expected in the graph:
  - export-registerRoutes
  - export-validateRequest
  - export-handleWebsocket
  - export-buildRuntimeDependencies

Existing CrossLinks:
- M-API-HTTP -> M-API-JOBS relation="routes-to"
- M-API-HTTP -> M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION relation="provides-internal-control-plane-to"
- M-API-HTTP -> M-WORKER-REPORT relation="provides-internal-control-plane-to"
- M-API-HTTP -> M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH relation="provides-internal-control-plane-to"
      ]]></graph-entry-excerpt>
      <dependency-contract-summaries>
        <dependency-1 module="M-CONTRACTS">Parity verification uses the frozen public and internal worker contract surface as the source of truth for every route and envelope.</dependency-1>
        <dependency-2 module="M-API-JOBS">Job lineage, child reuse, retry, and cancel semantics remain jobs-owned; HTTP only proves route-level parity and envelope correctness.</dependency-2>
        <dependency-3 module="M-API-STORAGE">Artifact resolution and authoritative polling snapshots remain storage-backed and must stay readable under the cutover stack.</dependency-3>
        <dependency-4 module="M-API-EVENTS">WebSocket and webhook behavior are verified as delivery layers while polling stays authoritative.</dependency-4>
      </dependency-contract-summaries>
      <verification-excerpt><![CDATA[
VerificationPlan / V-M-API-HTTP / CutoverParity:
- Module check: go test ./... -run ApiHttp
- Success scenario: public endpoints shape accepted requests and responses according to the canonical contract, including the separate combined upload route.
- Failure scenario: invalid UUIDs, missing webhook URLs, oversized uploads, and unsupported source URLs return stable error envelopes.
- Required marker: [ApiHttp][validateRequest][BLOCK_VALIDATE_REQUEST_AND_SHAPE_RESPONSE]
- Required assertion: internal worker endpoints must not be confused with public client endpoints.
- Wave follow-up: run API handler tests with real multipart and JSON fixtures for both per-file and combined upload routes.
- Phase follow-up: full route regression against generated SDKs and manual curl smoke checks.
- Cutover parity evidence:
  - compose-wide smoke verification passes with all required services healthy;
  - functional parity against the frozen acceptance matrix is demonstrated;
  - the old single-process runtime path is not removed until parity evidence exists.
      ]]></verification-excerpt>
      <step-local-verification>
        <command-1>go test ./... -run ApiHttp</command-1>
        <command-2>Full route regression with multipart, combined upload, URL, child-job, artifact, cancel, retry, WebSocket, and internal worker fixtures against the live stack.</command-2>
        <command-3>Acceptance-matrix parity replay proving the new stack covers the frozen baseline before legacy cutover.</command-3>
        <evidence-1>HTTP route behavior stays contract-shaped for both public clients and internal worker-control flows under the full stack.</evidence-1>
        <evidence-2>Cutover is blocked until parity evidence exists; route-level deltas remain narrow and evidence-driven.</evidence-2>
        <evidence-3>Local browser CORS remains an HTTP boundary behavior and does not move business logic into Web UI.</evidence-3>
      </step-local-verification>
      <expected-graph-delta-fields>
        <field-1>imports: route dependency set should stay stable across M-CONTRACTS, M-API-JOBS, M-API-STORAGE, M-API-QUEUE, and M-API-EVENTS.</field-1>
        <field-2>exports: confirm route registration, request validation, and WebSocket entry stay the stable public HTTP exports.</field-2>
        <field-3>annotations: refine only route-level annotations surfaced by parity gaps; do not move business ownership into HTTP.</field-3>
        <field-4>CrossLinks: preserve current route-to-jobs and route-to-worker-control boundaries.</field-4>
      </expected-graph-delta-fields>
      <expected-verification-delta-fields>
        <field-1>test-files: expand route-level fixture coverage under `apps/api/internal/api/*_test.go` only where parity evidence proves a gap.</field-1>
        <field-2>module-checks: preserve `go test ./... -run ApiHttp` and add live-stack acceptance replay commands only as parity verification.</field-2>
        <field-3>required-log-markers: preserve `[ApiHttp][validateRequest][BLOCK_VALIDATE_REQUEST_AND_SHAPE_RESPONSE]`.</field-3>
        <field-4>follow-up-checks: legacy path removal remains blocked on explicit cutover evidence, not on assumptions.</field-4>
      </expected-verification-delta-fields>
      <open-cutover-gates>
        <gate-1 id="CUTOVER-PARITY-HTTP">Run live-stack route regression for multipart upload, combined upload, URL submission, child-job creation, artifact resolution, cancel, retry, WebSocket, and internal worker-control routes.</gate-1>
        <gate-2 id="CUTOVER-WORKER-E2E">Prove worker execution against real MinIO and API claim/finalize paths for transcription, report, and deep-research jobs.</gate-2>
        <gate-3 id="CUTOVER-ADAPTER-PARITY">Replay Web UI browser smoke, Telegram UX, and MCP tool-level live API integration against the same stack.</gate-3>
        <gate-4 id="CUTOVER-FAILURE-PATHS">Close storage, queue, webhook, and WebSocket failure-path smokes that remain open in verification-plan.xml.</gate-4>
        <gate-5 id="CUTOVER-LEGACY-REMOVAL">Delete or replace the old single-process runtime path only after all previous gates pass.</gate-5>
      </open-cutover-gates>
      <notes>
        <note-1>This is a verification-heavy packet and should not be used as a pretext for broad control-plane refactors.</note-1>
        <note-2>Use first-divergent-block reasoning: if parity fails outside HTTP, hand off through failure packets instead of patching blindly in the route layer.</note-2>
      </notes>
    </ExecutionPacket>
  </ProjectExecutionPackets>

  <ProjectFailurePackets>
    <FailurePacket packet-id="M-CONTRACTS-wave-1-webhook-validation-drift" module="M-CONTRACTS" verification-ref="V-M-CONTRACTS">
      <scenario>Webhook create requests accept `delivery.strategy=webhook` without requiring `delivery.webhook.url`, or return a different job snapshot envelope than polling create flows.</scenario>
      <contract-ref>M-CONTRACTS / V-M-CONTRACTS / TestingStrategy/ContractTests / DF-001 / DF-003 / DF-007</contract-ref>
      <expected-evidence>
        <marker-1>[Contracts][validateContractSurface][BLOCK_VALIDATE_CONTRACT_SURFACE]</marker-1>
        <assertion-1>All create flows default or validate `delivery` consistently and return the same canonical `job` or `jobs` snapshot shape after normalization.</assertion-1>
        <assertion-2>`POST /v1/jobs/{job_id}/retry` stays non-idempotent and is not merged into create-idempotency rules.</assertion-2>
      </expected-evidence>
      <observed-evidence>
        <log-1>[Contracts][validateContractSurface][BLOCK_VALIDATE_CONTRACT_SURFACE] emitted before schema comparison failed</log-1>
        <trace-1>create-transcription-upload schema accepted `delivery_strategy=webhook` with no webhook URL</trace-1>
        <trace-2>Webhook or WebSocket envelope drifted away from the canonical job snapshot or delivery shape</trace-2>
      </observed-evidence>
      <first-divergent-block>BLOCK_VALIDATE_CONTRACT_SURFACE</first-divergent-block>
      <suggested-next-action>Inspect the shared delivery, job snapshot, and event-envelope schemas first, then re-compose route-specific schemas from those shared definitions instead of duplicating branches.</suggested-next-action>
    </FailurePacket>

    <FailurePacket packet-id="M-API-STORAGE-wave-2-artifact-persistence-order-drift" module="M-API-STORAGE" verification-ref="V-M-API-STORAGE">
      <scenario>Storage writes artifact or delivery rows even though MinIO persistence failed, or Phase-2 tables and constraints do not match the frozen PersistentModel.</scenario>
      <contract-ref>M-API-STORAGE / V-M-API-STORAGE / PersistentModel / StorageContract / Gate-Phase-2</contract-ref>
      <expected-evidence>
        <marker-1>[ApiStorage][persistJob][BLOCK_PERSIST_JOB_AND_ARTIFACT]</marker-1>
        <assertion-1>Artifact rows are created only after object upload succeeds.</assertion-1>
        <assertion-2>`job_submissions`, `job_events`, and `webhook_deliveries` exist with the required uniqueness and retry-state constraints.</assertion-2>
      </expected-evidence>
      <observed-evidence>
        <log-1>[ApiStorage][persistJob][BLOCK_PERSIST_JOB_AND_ARTIFACT] emitted before object-store confirmation or migration failure</log-1>
        <trace-1>Database row was inserted while MinIO upload or presigned-link resolution failed</trace-1>
        <trace-2>Migration smoke check showed missing Phase-2 tables or constraint drift</trace-2>
        <trace-3>Host-browser artifact resolution returned a presigned URL on Docker-internal `http://minio:9000`, making the link unreachable outside the compose network; the fix belongs in the storage public-presign endpoint contract, not in adapters.</trace-3>
      </observed-evidence>
      <first-divergent-block>BLOCK_PERSIST_JOB_AND_ARTIFACT</first-divergent-block>
      <suggested-next-action>Check migration order and object-store transaction boundaries first; restore storage-authoritative sequencing before inspecting downstream jobs or HTTP behavior.</suggested-next-action>
    </FailurePacket>

    <FailurePacket packet-id="M-API-STORAGE-wave-2-execution-claim-authority-drift" module="M-API-STORAGE" verification-ref="V-M-API-STORAGE">
      <scenario>Internal worker routes require `execution_id`, but Phase-2 storage does not materialize authoritative claim state that survives claim, progress, artifact, finalize, and cancel-check calls.</scenario>
      <contract-ref>M-API-STORAGE / InternalWorkerContract / Gate-Phase-2 / execution_id-authority</contract-ref>
      <expected-evidence>
        <assertion-1>Internal worker execution ids are backed by authoritative storage state instead of route-local or in-memory ownership signals.</assertion-1>
      </expected-evidence>
      <observed-evidence>
        <trace-1>InternalWorkerContract requires `execution_id`, but the storage schema or concrete state store exposes no authoritative execution-claim persistence.</trace-1>
        <trace-2>Claim, progress, artifact, finalize, or cancel-check behavior would need route-local or process-local shortcuts to honor the frozen contract.</trace-2>
      </observed-evidence>
      <first-divergent-block>execution_id-authority</first-divergent-block>
      <suggested-next-action>Materialize storage-owned execution-claim persistence first, then wire jobs and HTTP on top of that surface instead of patching claim behavior in route handlers.</suggested-next-action>
    </FailurePacket>

    <FailurePacket packet-id="M-API-QUEUE-wave-2-payload-retry-drift" module="M-API-QUEUE" verification-ref="V-M-API-QUEUE">
      <scenario>Queue payloads start carrying mutable job metadata, or deterministic business failures retry indefinitely instead of using SkipRetry.</scenario>
      <contract-ref>M-API-QUEUE / V-M-API-QUEUE / QueueContract / DF-004 / DF-005 / DF-006</contract-ref>
      <expected-evidence>
        <marker-1>[ApiQueue][enqueue][BLOCK_ENQUEUE_JOB]</marker-1>
        <assertion-1>Queue payload contains only `job_id` plus attempt metadata.</assertion-1>
        <assertion-2>Terminal claim rejection, authoritative cancel, missing required artifacts, invalid request data, and terminal model failures use SkipRetry.</assertion-2>
      </expected-evidence>
      <observed-evidence>
        <log-1>[ApiQueue][enqueue][BLOCK_ENQUEUE_JOB] emitted before queue test failed</log-1>
        <trace-1>Task payload serialized mutable job snapshots or delivery metadata</trace-1>
        <trace-2>Deterministic business error looped through transport retries instead of terminating</trace-2>
      </observed-evidence>
      <first-divergent-block>BLOCK_ENQUEUE_JOB</first-divergent-block>
      <suggested-next-action>Reduce the payload back to canonical task identity fields and re-check QueueContract ownership rules before touching job orchestration logic.</suggested-next-action>
    </FailurePacket>

    <FailurePacket packet-id="M-API-JOBS-wave-2-lineage-transition-drift" module="M-API-JOBS" verification-ref="V-M-API-JOBS">
      <scenario>Retry mutates a historical row, canonical child reuse is lost, or cancel and idempotency rules diverge from the frozen PublicApiContract.</scenario>
      <contract-ref>M-API-JOBS / V-M-API-JOBS / PublicApiContract / RetryPolicy / CancellationPolicy / DF-001 / DF-002 / DF-006 / DF-007</contract-ref>
      <expected-evidence>
        <marker-1>[ApiJobs][transitionJob][BLOCK_VALIDATE_AND_TRANSITION_JOB]</marker-1>
        <assertion-1>Retry creates a new lineage-linked row and does not copy artifacts or events from the source row.</assertion-1>
        <assertion-2>Create-child requests reuse the canonical child unless explicit retry is requested.</assertion-2>
      </expected-evidence>
      <observed-evidence>
        <log-1>[ApiJobs][transitionJob][BLOCK_VALIDATE_AND_TRANSITION_JOB] emitted before state assertion failed</log-1>
        <trace-1>Retry updated a terminal row in place or mutated historical artifacts</trace-1>
        <trace-2>Repeated report or deep-research create request spawned a sibling instead of returning the canonical child</trace-2>
      </observed-evidence>
      <first-divergent-block>BLOCK_VALIDATE_AND_TRANSITION_JOB</first-divergent-block>
      <suggested-next-action>Inspect jobs-level lineage and child-reuse rules first, then confirm storage and queue are still being treated as dependencies rather than sources of business semantics.</suggested-next-action>
    </FailurePacket>

    <FailurePacket packet-id="M-API-EVENTS-wave-2-polling-authority-drift" module="M-API-EVENTS" verification-ref="V-M-API-EVENTS">
      <scenario>Webhook delivery state is not durable across restarts, or WebSocket behavior becomes an authoritative state path instead of a low-latency delivery layer.</scenario>
      <contract-ref>M-API-EVENTS / V-M-API-EVENTS / WebSocketContract / WebhookDeliveryContract / Gate-Phase-2</contract-ref>
      <expected-evidence>
        <marker-1>[ApiEvents][emitJobEvent][BLOCK_EMIT_VERSIONED_EVENT]</marker-1>
        <assertion-1>One persisted job event maps to one versioned event emission.</assertion-1>
        <assertion-2>Polling remains authoritative even when WebSocket or webhook delivery succeeds.</assertion-2>
      </expected-evidence>
      <observed-evidence>
        <log-1>[ApiEvents][emitJobEvent][BLOCK_EMIT_VERSIONED_EVENT] emitted before event-delivery assertion failed</log-1>
        <trace-1>Webhook retry state disappeared after restart or retried with non-bounded semantics</trace-1>
        <trace-2>WebSocket reconnect path reused stale client state without REST reconciliation</trace-2>
      </observed-evidence>
      <first-divergent-block>BLOCK_EMIT_VERSIONED_EVENT</first-divergent-block>
      <suggested-next-action>Check append-only event persistence and durable webhook-delivery bookkeeping before touching UI consumers; then restore the polling-truth rule in the event layer.</suggested-next-action>
    </FailurePacket>

    <FailurePacket packet-id="M-API-HTTP-wave-2-route-boundary-drift" module="M-API-HTTP" verification-ref="V-M-API-HTTP">
      <scenario>Public and internal worker routes are conflated, or request-validation failures stop returning the canonical contract envelopes.</scenario>
      <contract-ref>M-API-HTTP / V-M-API-HTTP / PublicApiContract / InternalWorkerContract / Gate-Phase-2</contract-ref>
      <expected-evidence>
        <marker-1>[ApiHttp][validateRequest][BLOCK_VALIDATE_REQUEST_AND_SHAPE_RESPONSE]</marker-1>
        <assertion-1>Invalid UUIDs, missing webhook URLs, oversized uploads, and unsupported source URLs return stable error envelopes.</assertion-1>
        <assertion-2>Internal worker claim, progress, artifact, finalize, and cancel-check routes remain explicit and separate from public client endpoints.</assertion-2>
      </expected-evidence>
      <observed-evidence>
        <log-1>[ApiHttp][validateRequest][BLOCK_VALIDATE_REQUEST_AND_SHAPE_RESPONSE] emitted before handler assertion failed</log-1>
        <trace-1>Missing webhook URL or multipart validation error returned a non-canonical envelope</trace-1>
        <trace-2>Public router exposed internal worker-control paths by convention or reused public request validation in the wrong direction</trace-2>
      </observed-evidence>
      <first-divergent-block>BLOCK_VALIDATE_REQUEST_AND_SHAPE_RESPONSE</first-divergent-block>
      <suggested-next-action>Restore route-layer separation first, then validate request and response shaping strictly against the frozen M-CONTRACTS surface before inspecting downstream module behavior.</suggested-next-action>
    </FailurePacket>

    <FailurePacket packet-id="M-WORKER-COMMON-wave-3-internal-control-plane-drift" module="M-WORKER-COMMON" verification-ref="V-M-WORKER-COMMON">
      <scenario>Shared worker helpers bypass the canonical internal control-plane contract, or artifact-helper payloads drift away from frozen finalize and artifact DTOs.</scenario>
      <contract-ref>M-WORKER-COMMON / V-M-WORKER-COMMON / Phase-3 step-1 / MigrationMapping</contract-ref>
      <expected-evidence>
        <marker-1>[WorkerCommon][callInternalApi][BLOCK_CALL_INTERNAL_CONTROL_PLANE]</marker-1>
        <assertion-1>Claim, progress, artifact, finalize, and cancel-check helpers emit contract-shaped payloads only.</assertion-1>
      </expected-evidence>
      <observed-evidence>
        <log-1>[WorkerCommon][callInternalApi][BLOCK_CALL_INTERNAL_CONTROL_PLANE] emitted before helper contract assertion failed</log-1>
        <trace-1>Worker helper called a local shortcut or emitted malformed artifact or finalize payload fields</trace-1>
      </observed-evidence>
      <first-divergent-block>BLOCK_CALL_INTERNAL_CONTROL_PLANE</first-divergent-block>
      <suggested-next-action>Restore worker-common transport ownership first, then revalidate the helper payloads directly against the frozen worker-control DTOs before touching any worker-specific module.</suggested-next-action>
    </FailurePacket>

    <FailurePacket packet-id="M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION-wave-3-artifact-order-drift" module="M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION" verification-ref="V-M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION">
      <scenario>Transcription worker finalizes success before all transcript artifacts exist, or combined-media inputs lose ordering before the final transcription pass.</scenario>
      <contract-ref>M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION / V-M-WORKER-TRANSCRIPTION / DF-001 / DF-002 / DF-007 / Phase-3 step-2</contract-ref>
      <expected-evidence>
        <marker-1>[WorkerTranscription][runTranscription][BLOCK_EXECUTE_TRANSCRIPTION_PIPELINE]</marker-1>
        <assertion-1>Plain, segmented, and DOCX transcript artifacts all exist before success finalization.</assertion-1>
        <assertion-2>Combined-media jobs concatenate ordered inputs before the final transcription pass.</assertion-2>
      </expected-evidence>
      <observed-evidence>
        <log-1>[WorkerTranscription][runTranscription][BLOCK_EXECUTE_TRANSCRIPTION_PIPELINE] emitted before artifact-order assertion failed</log-1>
        <trace-1>Success finalization happened with missing transcript artifact rows or files</trace-1>
        <trace-2>Combined-input path skipped ordered concatenation or transcribed inputs independently</trace-2>
      </observed-evidence>
      <first-divergent-block>BLOCK_EXECUTE_TRANSCRIPTION_PIPELINE</first-divergent-block>
      <suggested-next-action>Inspect ordered-input materialization and artifact-finalization sequencing first; restore the preserved transcript artifact contract before touching Telegram or UI consumers.</suggested-next-action>
    </FailurePacket>

    <FailurePacket packet-id="M-WORKER-REPORT-wave-4-subprocess-cancel-drift" module="M-WORKER-REPORT" verification-ref="V-M-WORKER-REPORT">
      <scenario>Report worker loses deterministic subprocess failure handling, or cancellation does not terminate `cglm` before finalizing `canceled`.</scenario>
      <contract-ref>M-WORKER-REPORT / V-M-WORKER-REPORT / Phase-4 step-1 / DF-004 / DF-006</contract-ref>
      <expected-evidence>
        <marker-1>[WorkerReport][runReport][BLOCK_EXECUTE_REPORT_PIPELINE]</marker-1>
        <assertion-1>Missing binary, timeout, and non-zero exit produce deterministic worker failures.</assertion-1>
        <assertion-2>Cancellation terminates subprocess execution before finalizing `canceled`.</assertion-2>
      </expected-evidence>
      <observed-evidence>
        <log-1>[WorkerReport][runReport][BLOCK_EXECUTE_REPORT_PIPELINE] emitted before subprocess assertion failed</log-1>
        <trace-1>cglm process outlived cancel handling or terminal state emission</trace-1>
        <trace-2>Report worker surfaced non-deterministic subprocess errors or partial artifact output</trace-2>
      </observed-evidence>
      <first-divergent-block>BLOCK_EXECUTE_REPORT_PIPELINE</first-divergent-block>
      <suggested-next-action>Restore subprocess lifecycle ownership inside the report worker first, then re-check artifact registration and cancel sequencing against the worker-common helpers.</suggested-next-action>
    </FailurePacket>

    <FailurePacket packet-id="M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH-wave-4-phase-output-drift" module="M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH" verification-ref="V-M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH">
      <scenario>Deep-research worker emits success without required phase artifacts or final markdown output, or blocked writes surface as partial success.</scenario>
      <contract-ref>M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH / V-M-WORKER-DEEP-RESEARCH / Phase-4 step-2 / DF-005 / DF-006</contract-ref>
      <expected-evidence>
        <marker-1>[WorkerDeepResearch][runDeepResearch][BLOCK_EXECUTE_DEEP_RESEARCH_PIPELINE]</marker-1>
        <assertion-1>Terminal success is emitted only when required phase artifacts and final markdown output are present.</assertion-1>
      </expected-evidence>
      <observed-evidence>
        <log-1>[WorkerDeepResearch][runDeepResearch][BLOCK_EXECUTE_DEEP_RESEARCH_PIPELINE] emitted before phase-output assertion failed</log-1>
        <trace-1>Required phase artifact or final markdown output was missing at success finalization time</trace-1>
        <trace-2>Blocked writes or timeout paths surfaced partial success instead of deterministic failure</trace-2>
      </observed-evidence>
      <first-divergent-block>BLOCK_EXECUTE_DEEP_RESEARCH_PIPELINE</first-divergent-block>
      <suggested-next-action>Inspect required artifact checks and terminal finalization order first; restore deterministic failure handling before touching API child-job flows or compose runtime concerns.</suggested-next-action>
    </FailurePacket>

    <FailurePacket packet-id="M-WEB-UI-wave-5-polling-truth-drift" module="M-WEB-UI" verification-ref="V-M-WEB-UI">
      <scenario>Web UI starts trusting stale WebSocket state as authoritative, or admin and artifact actions infer client-side outcomes instead of re-reading API truth.</scenario>
      <contract-ref>M-WEB-UI / V-M-WEB-UI / Phase-5 step-1 / DF-003 / polling-truth-rule</contract-ref>
      <expected-evidence>
        <marker-1>[WebUi][reconcileState][BLOCK_RECONCILE_POLLING_AND_WS_STATE]</marker-1>
        <assertion-1>UI re-fetches from REST on WebSocket reconnect or version gap.</assertion-1>
      </expected-evidence>
      <observed-evidence>
        <log-1>[WebUi][reconcileState][BLOCK_RECONCILE_POLLING_AND_WS_STATE] emitted before state-reconciliation assertion failed</log-1>
        <trace-1>Client retained stale WebSocket state without REST reconciliation</trace-1>
        <trace-2>Expired artifact link or admin action outcome was guessed client-side instead of re-read from the API</trace-2>
      </observed-evidence>
      <first-divergent-block>BLOCK_RECONCILE_POLLING_AND_WS_STATE</first-divergent-block>
      <suggested-next-action>Restore the polling-truth rule first, then narrow the fix to UI reconciliation or action-refresh boundaries instead of patching API semantics blindly.</suggested-next-action>
    </FailurePacket>

    <FailurePacket packet-id="M-TELEGRAM-ADAPTER-wave-5-ux-coupling-drift" module="M-TELEGRAM-ADAPTER" verification-ref="V-M-TELEGRAM-ADAPTER">
      <scenario>Telegram flows regain local execution coupling, or media-group and callback paths bypass API lineage and child-job rules.</scenario>
      <contract-ref>M-TELEGRAM-ADAPTER / V-M-TELEGRAM-ADAPTER / Phase-5 step-2 / DF-001 / DF-004 / DF-005 / DF-007</contract-ref>
      <expected-evidence>
        <marker-1>[TelegramAdapter][handleMedia][BLOCK_SUBMIT_AND_WAIT_FOR_JOB]</marker-1>
        <assertion-1>Default Telegram delivery strategy remains polling.</assertion-1>
        <assertion-2>Media groups map to the combined transcription flow instead of the per-file upload flow.</assertion-2>
      </expected-evidence>
      <observed-evidence>
        <log-1>[TelegramAdapter][handleMedia][BLOCK_SUBMIT_AND_WAIT_FOR_JOB] emitted before adapter parity assertion failed</log-1>
        <trace-1>Bot imported local execution helpers again or handled lineage-sensitive actions outside the API</trace-1>
        <trace-2>Media-group flow spawned multiple unrelated jobs or callback flow bypassed API child-job rules</trace-2>
      </observed-evidence>
      <first-divergent-block>BLOCK_SUBMIT_AND_WAIT_FOR_JOB</first-divergent-block>
      <suggested-next-action>Restore thin-adapter boundaries first, then verify combined-media submission and callback-to-API mapping before changing worker or API business logic.</suggested-next-action>
    </FailurePacket>

    <FailurePacket packet-id="M-MCP-ADAPTER-wave-5-thin-boundary-drift" module="M-MCP-ADAPTER" verification-ref="V-M-MCP-ADAPTER">
      <scenario>MCP tool handlers absorb hidden business logic or require direct DB, queue, or MinIO access instead of delegating through the HTTP API.</scenario>
      <contract-ref>M-MCP-ADAPTER / V-M-MCP-ADAPTER / Phase-5 step-3 / thin-adapter rule</contract-ref>
      <expected-evidence>
        <marker-1>[McpAdapter][mapToolToApi][BLOCK_MAP_MCP_TOOL_TO_API_CALL]</marker-1>
        <assertion-1>MCP never requires direct DB, queue, or MinIO access.</assertion-1>
      </expected-evidence>
      <observed-evidence>
        <log-1>[McpAdapter][mapToolToApi][BLOCK_MAP_MCP_TOOL_TO_API_CALL] emitted before thin-boundary assertion failed</log-1>
        <trace-1>Tool handler attempted direct infra access or embedded business rules already owned by the API</trace-1>
        <trace-2>Adapter-level validation or error propagation drifted away from canonical API contract envelopes</trace-2>
      </observed-evidence>
      <first-divergent-block>BLOCK_MAP_MCP_TOOL_TO_API_CALL</first-divergent-block>
      <suggested-next-action>Reduce MCP back to pure tool-to-API mapping first, then re-run contract-shaped response checks before editing any control-plane module.</suggested-next-action>
    </FailurePacket>

    <FailurePacket packet-id="M-INFRA-COMPOSE-wave-6-stack-hardening-drift" module="M-INFRA-COMPOSE" verification-ref="V-M-INFRA-COMPOSE">
      <scenario>Compose config remains valid on paper, but live stack startup, healthcheck convergence, or persistent volume wiring fails during the hardening wave.</scenario>
      <contract-ref>M-INFRA-COMPOSE / V-M-INFRA-COMPOSE / Phase-6 step-1 / CutoverParity</contract-ref>
      <expected-evidence>
        <marker-1>[InfraCompose][verifyLocalStack][BLOCK_VERIFY_LOCAL_STACK_HEALTH]</marker-1>
        <assertion-1>Compose smoke verification proves startup order, healthcheck convergence, and persistent volume wiring before cutover.</assertion-1>
      </expected-evidence>
      <observed-evidence>
        <log-1>[InfraCompose][verifyLocalStack][BLOCK_VERIFY_LOCAL_STACK_HEALTH] emitted before live-stack assertion failed</log-1>
        <trace-1>Stack required manual startup ordering or one or more service healthchecks never converged</trace-1>
        <trace-2>Persistent volume or init-script expectations failed despite `docker compose config` remaining valid</trace-2>
        <trace-3>Default stack excluded a required runtime service or still resolved it to a placeholder runtime image, so health convergence could not begin.</trace-3>
      </observed-evidence>
      <first-divergent-block>BLOCK_VERIFY_LOCAL_STACK_HEALTH</first-divergent-block>
      <suggested-next-action>If the first live-smoke failure is a missing, profile-gated, or placeholder runtime service, stop in infra and hand off to the owning runtime packet first; patch compose-local startup and health boundaries only after real entrypoints exist.</suggested-next-action>
    </FailurePacket>

    <FailurePacket packet-id="M-API-HTTP-wave-6-cutover-parity-drift" module="M-API-HTTP" verification-ref="V-M-API-HTTP">
      <scenario>Full-stack parity against the frozen acceptance matrix fails, but the first divergent block is still the HTTP boundary rather than jobs, workers, events, or compose wiring.</scenario>
      <contract-ref>M-API-HTTP / V-M-API-HTTP / Phase-6 step-2 / CutoverParity / PublicApiContract</contract-ref>
      <expected-evidence>
        <marker-1>[ApiHttp][validateRequest][BLOCK_VALIDATE_REQUEST_AND_SHAPE_RESPONSE]</marker-1>
        <assertion-1>Combined upload, URL create, child-job, artifact, cancel, retry, WebSocket, and internal worker routes remain contract-shaped under the live stack.</assertion-1>
      </expected-evidence>
      <observed-evidence>
        <log-1>[ApiHttp][validateRequest][BLOCK_VALIDATE_REQUEST_AND_SHAPE_RESPONSE] emitted before parity assertion failed</log-1>
        <trace-1>Acceptance replay found a route-level envelope or validation drift under the live stack</trace-1>
        <trace-2>Cutover evidence was incomplete, or legacy-path removal was attempted before parity proof existed</trace-2>
      </observed-evidence>
      <first-divergent-block>BLOCK_VALIDATE_REQUEST_AND_SHAPE_RESPONSE</first-divergent-block>
      <suggested-next-action>Patch only the proven route-level divergence first; if parity failure originates downstream, stop and hand off through the owning module instead of broadening the HTTP packet.</suggested-next-action>
    </FailurePacket>
  </ProjectFailurePackets>
</OperationalPackets>
